<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Blog | RememberLenny]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-13T01:28:14-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Leonard Kiyoshi Bogdonoff]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Opposite of poverty]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2014/02/13/opposite-of-poverty/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-13T00:45:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2014/02/13/opposite-of-poverty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What is the opposite of poverty?</p>

<p>My roommate and I had dinner tonight. We don&rsquo;t normally eat together and in the past we havn&rsquo;t spent time together. I feel a distance between the two of us that stems from my own perspectives subconcious judgements. I allow these personal options form, because they help me understand what I believe. Without reflecting on them, I wouldn&rsquo;t be able to confidently recognize where I am and where I want to be.</p>

<p>Our discussion began with cultural observations about the future. I observe that global cultural shifts are drastically different from the past. The urbanized and rural communities are growing further apart. Urban centers are culturally similar around the world. Rural communities are the cultural unique reminence of the world.</p>

<p>I spent last year in China, Japan, Germany, Ecuador, and Peru. I traveled around the USA, from the California, New Mexico, Texas, New York, Massachusets, and Virgina. My short trips helped reinforce my opinions about global economic differences. The time in China and Ecuador were most influential.</p>

<p>Although I lived in China for nearly a year, the disparity in wealth was not uncomfortable. Occasionally, I saw an expensive car. Soon after, I would see a group of elder woman picking up recycling materials. The dycotomy of capital was obvious. I lived there, so I didnt take it to heart. By the end of my time, I felt at home. I found the places I liked to eat, the friends I spent time with, and the tasks to occupy my time. The tasks were evidently value creative. The comfort I experienced was my blindfold.</p>

<p>I visited Ecuador as an outsider. I attempted to reconvene with seven friends living in around the US. The trip was spontaneous and successfully executed. With little planning and no language competency, I spent two weeks Ecuador and Peru. My time was interupted by a brief cold I caught. The cold was the result of less than optimal sleeping conditions. The diet and deprived sleeping habits surely did not help.</p>

<p>Poverty was apparent in Ecuador. The country&rsquo;s infrustructure struggles as a whole. Primary gross domestic exports were fruits, flowers, and oil. The majority of the country exchanged labor for small payment. People&rsquo;s monthy salary was close to 300 dollars a month. A really good monthly salary was 600 for a young man. 600 dollars for 30 days. 300 dollars.</p>

<p>When I say poverty was apparent, I stress the state of life. People were full of agency. Commerce was busy, possibly even budding. People ran small businesses. Chain establishments existed in full force in Quito. Churchs, museums, entertainment opportunities, and youth culture were well developed. Still, poverty was apparent.</p>

<p>Meals were bland. Small piece of chicken, a bowl of soup, and rice was lunch. Amuoreso. Or something of that. Amuoreso was also dinner. Sometimes it was also breakfast. When I say it was each of these, I mean that diversity in food choices was small. Various options were avaliable, but not widely chosen because of cost. Perhaps the same can be said anywhere, but the lack of food selection was apparent.</p>

<p>Buses would regularly stop to let on traveling salesmen and woman. Bus rides included opportunities to purchase incense, fried pork loins, small meals, and bags of fruit. Looking back, the choice of foods was similar to rural China. Ecuador&rsquo;s distinguishing factor was the approach to selling. Sales persons would get on a moving bus and make an announecment in the front area. Based on their pitch, some riders would show interest, while most would not.</p>

<p>I was impacted by Ecuador most when I returned to the US. Upon arriving in the Newerk airport and taking the metro into New York, I recovered from my cold. Once arriving into the city, I was immediately approached by numerous homeless persons asking for money. No more than 12 hours before, I was in a country where even the poorest people sought honest ways to earn a living. In New York, I felt like the poorest of the rich did not seek a geographically equivilent means.</p>

<p>The opposite of poverty is justice. Daisaku Ikeda states this in numerous occasions within his speeches and dialogues with world leaders. Justice in economic opportunity. Justice in opportunity to experience the world. Justice in personal judgement.</p>

<p>I stress that the people I met in China and Ecuador had agency. Especially those from less affluent communities. Reflecting, I may even say that those from wealthier countries were less aware of their own agency to make change in the world as a whole. They instead frequented the thoughts of what they could not do. This was not something I saw in the youth of other places. Perhaps this is a negative consequence of being provided so much opportunity.</p>

<p>In anycase, my interest in the startup space or the industries revolving around educating people is justice. How can I better identify the root of my local and global communities issues. What injustice can I recognize and take action against? I must stress that this will not happen with intellectual masturbation. I do not seek fame, wealth, or power. I desire to create value.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The opposite of poverty]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2014/02/13/the-opposite-of-poverty/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-13T00:44:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2014/02/13/the-opposite-of-poverty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I returned my Google Glass after 30 days]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2014/01/05/i-return-ed-my-google-glass-after-30-days/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-05T12:06:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2014/01/05/i-return-ed-my-google-glass-after-30-days</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/LKBG-TG/blog/BdO-8TfCIAAODcb.jpg" alt="Glass wearing roommates" /></p>

<h1>I returned Google Glass</h1>

<p>At the end of November, I was one of the thousands of people who receive the next round of invitations for Google Glass. After the v2 explorer edition was announced, I responded to an email from the Google Developers Group meetup in New York City. The email offered a Google Glass invitation code to anyone interested in acquiring the device.</p>

<p>Initially, I was completely sure I would want the device. I immediately responded to the email and excitedly told my roommate. Based on the timing of the invitation code request, I had to wait over the Thanksgiving holiday period before hearing a reply. During the time, I went home and spent an extended period researching the Google Glass status.</p>

<p>Many of the blogs online weren&rsquo;t very diverse in opinion. There were the two camps of: &ldquo;Its not where it could be, but I love the potential&rdquo; and &ldquo;This thing is way too expensive for what it can do&rdquo;. Through reading state of Google Glass, I found that the battery life was poor, there was no integration with iOS (since December, this changed), the app eco-system was not extensive, and you couldn&rsquo;t use it with perscription glasses. While I ocilated on my perspective toward buying Glass, I decided to go ahead with it.</p>

<p>Upon receiving confirmation of an invitation code, I setup my pick up date. Suprisingly, after I told my roommate, he applied for a Glass invite and was able to get a pair. After seeing his pair, I was reinvigorated to experiement with the new technology. In fact, because he had a pair, I started to imagine a number of possibilities involving multiple Glass users.</p>

<p><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-xQ-_ghQOu4c/UsuB-frTauI/AAAAAAAABlo/FS4Dk_FrKPM/w1679-h1233-no/20131211_151919_092.jpg" alt="Glass in NYC" /></p>

<h2>Wearing Glass</h2>

<p>Wearing Glass in New York isnt too obscure. My roommate says it make you a &ldquo;C class celebrity&rdquo;. People look at you in the subway. Glass becomes a easy point to start a conversation. I even feel like you get special treatment at resturants. Regardless, it also becomes an impediment for feeling comfortable around people. Its an expensive piece of technology that draws attention.</p>

<p>I found that initially I was very interested in the different applications offered on Glass. The most interesting application is called Field Trips. Field Trips uses your current location to feed you relevant information about places around you. For example, Field Trips pulls in historic information about the landmarks around you. When you pass the area, you get a &ldquo;card&rdquo; that tells you the areas significance. There was a building in my community that I really admired, but never knew its historic significance. After walking by the building while wearing Glass, I got a &ldquo;card&rdquo; about the building. This blew my mind.</p>

<p>In most of December, Glass didnt have an iOS app. As a result, there was very limited functionality. There were no maps, very little SMS integration, and quickly drained phone battery. Even with these limitations, wearing Glass was awesome.</p>

<p>In mid-December, Glass updated itself overnight and introduced new features. This was impressive. The coolest was a &ldquo;Wink&rdquo; recognition feature that was not previously accessible. This feature allowed you to take pictures by winking with your right eye. Although the wink detection would occasionally lose calibration, the feature was very impressive.</p>

<p>Around the same time, the iOS application was released. This gave the Glass the ability to integrate with the iPhone. With the iOS app, Glass users could get directions without an Android device. This was very useful, but still not as impressive as I hoped. Even in the cold December weather, I found it easier to pull out my iPhone and look on Google Maps. When I needed to go to obscure addresses, it became impossible to &ldquo;speak&rdquo; the appropriate address.</p>

<p>My biggest struggle was the limited user interface on the Glass. While the device itself is best fit for voice activation, you can also use a number of gestures. I found  the current interface too one-dimensional. When trying to set a Timer or procede through a list of application options, finding and selecting the prefered choice was difficult. Im sure this will be improved and no longer be an issue in the future.</p>

<p><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-uGQmw5kMcjA/UsuCajkElDI/AAAAAAAABmc/koH801E_JCk/w1679-h1233-no/20131210_152656_862.jpg" alt="Social implications of wearing Glass" /></p>

<h2>Personal impressions</h2>

<p>The reason Im returning Glass is less to do with the technology and more to do with the social implications. I had some great use cases, such as ease of recording personal interviews, as well as some bad acusations from stragners. Overall, the response from people was more positive than anything. People wanted to know about the &ldquo;cool looking glasses&rdquo;. Most lay people don&rsquo;t follow tech news, so they have no idea what the Glass is. I found that there was a higher population of young men who responded to Glass positively. Oppositely, I found the largest group of negative responses to come from middle-aged woman.</p>

<p>My biggest issue with Glass was the disruptive quality when looking at or talking with people. Glass doesn&rsquo;t disrupt your field of view, but it does feel like a barrier when interacting with other people. Once talking to someone, the Glass can be easily ignored, but I always felt a sense of discomfort.</p>

<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/LKBG-TG/blog/youngfolks.jpg" alt="Letting other people wear glass" /></p>

<p>My greatest joy with Glass was letting other people wear it. I found that younger people were very adept and using the voice activated commands. Oppositely, people in the twentys would wear the Glass and passively wait for something to happen. Adults who I had wear the Glass were often impressed by the device, but not as interested in trying it on.</p>

<p>After the honeymoon phase, I found myself using the Glass as a glorified watch. It because very easy to look at the time. I can imagine that great applications would be able to provide very valuable snippets of information with ease. For the time being, the information that is being served is not personally convincing for the need to have Glass. For the time being, even the best Glass apps are accessible via mobile devices. The moment Glass will shine is when apps are exclusively avaliable for Glass.</p>

<p><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/LKBG-TG/blog/glassnomore.jpg" alt="Driving a car with Glass" /></p>

<h2>Reason for returning</h2>

<p>I am returning Glass because I feel guilty about how much it costs. Buying the Glass was not a financial burden. As a software developer, I can justify expensive technology purchases because if they benefit my quality of life. Even if I dont use the device frequently, I would justify the value if it was useful when needed. I found this to be the case with buying a nice moniter for use at home and a high quality light laptop.</p>

<p>Still, the notion that I paid $1500 for the Glass felt obscure. Between the number of people who work low-paying hourly jobs, my mother included, I felt it was ridiculous to have such an expensive luxury item. The Glass would require more than a months worth of paychecks for most people to buy. Knowing that I was wearing the thing around without having much utilitive value kept reminding me how I was wasting the financial capital invested into the piece of technology.</p>

<p>If the device was a third of the cost, I could begin to justify the cost. For the time being, I am embarrased to be paying two months rent to feel apart of an exclusive group. While I think its amazing, I dont feel comfortable participating.</p>

<p><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-KNRJ9zecDTM/Ust9B-3KrKI/AAAAAAAABjM/3tgjFg308bE/w1012-h568-no/20131222_091642_791.mp4" alt="Driving a car with Glass" /></p>

<h2>Overall thoughts</h2>

<p>Considering my grievances about the user experience, I know these will be worked out. I have no question that the team working on Glass (officially and unofficially) are building amazing software. The potential for having a freely accessible camera and screen is brilliant. I can imagine security guards with Glass networks. Having a network of other &ldquo;eyes&rdquo; that you could access at the command of a voice seems useful in a number of professional use cases. I can see great social implications where people can see digital geo-fence activated messages based on their social networks. The Glass-like technologies have only jsut begun. I will be waiting with excitement to see the continued maturation of the Glass platform and users.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/12/31/on-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-31T10:10:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/12/31/on-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Between ending the year with well wishes to friends and family, I reflect.</p>

<h1>*-2013</h1>

<p>This is the beginning of a yearly tradition. At 24, I took many steps this year. Since living in China last year and actively painting the streets of Shanghai, I have settled down in New York City. Looking over the year is necessary for reflect on the progress made so far. I didn&rsquo;t do this for 2012, but there are so many people I am deeply appreciative to. Mainly the BMC artists, Franck&rsquo;s bistro staff, StageBack Gallery, KenasHome, Wealthy Sources, Flying Turtle Coffee, iTalki team, Techyizu volunteers, XinCheJian members, Converse co-workers, the diaspora of SGI members, and Ariel. The roughness of getting settled and the surreality of being in China made it one of the best memories of my life. I will never forget skateboarding around town while holding the backs of electric scooters.</p>

<p>After having returned to the US in December, I arrived at my parents home with horrible jet-lag, dwindling savings, and the single goal of finishing college. After returning home for two weeks, I purchased a bike, thinking I would stay in Southern California, but soon decided to make my next move. I preface the year with a brief tour of my friends in the US. Simultaneously, I decided to lay the groundwork for finding a job by identifying my value in the job market.</p>

<h2>January</h2>

<p>I started January with a road-trip from Orange County, California to Ryan&rsquo;s house in New Mexico. We drove through Sedona Arizona, where we took a pit stop and hiked around. I clearly remember trying to pet a cute dog that ran by, and being bit. The jeans I wore still have the teeth marks in the left leg.</p>

<p>After a few days on Ryan&rsquo;s couch, I flew from El Paso, Texas to Oakland, California. I crashed at Caitlin and Kyle&rsquo;s apartment near Clement street in San Francisco. I attended the MediaX conference at Stanford, where I saw a number of speakers, one being Larry Lesig. The ideas on learning analytics, crowd-powered systems, and social media analysis reinforced my perspective on the academic paper I would later present in February. I was fortunate to spend time with Whitney, Raimi, and Juju. Later that week, I was scheduled to fly to Detroit, but I decided to cancel that leg to attend the SLC education hackathon in Palo Alto. At the SLC, I met Joshua and Gary, whom I would later discuss developing &ldquo;Lesson Overflow&rdquo;. My time in San Francisco ended with meeting old friends from preschool.</p>

<p>From San Francisco, I flew to New York city, where I would later be moving. Unbeknownst to me, I was familiarizing myself with the community I would be living in a year later. I stayed with Jihii and Carley for a few days and interviewed a principle of a local KIPP school. After spending time at cafes and progressing on my review of Soka Education, I took a bus to Boston and visited Elaine. The Boston trip was brief, but productive in that I met with Eric for dinner.</p>

<p>In leaving Boston on the bus, I coincidentally sat next to an SGI member I had met years earlier. From Boston, I went DC to visit more friends and see Obama&rsquo;s inauguration. In DC, I vetted my understanding of the growing MOOC popularity and prepared for my return back to California. After spending a few days with Heidi and Corey, I received a last minute acceptance to a educational tech venture capital conference in New York. I changed my travel plans to head home to California and returned back to New York again.</p>

<p>After the conference, I made my way back to California. Believing I would be staying in California, I sought out a job opportunity with GOOD magazine and attended a hackathon at Google. I led a group project on Glassrooms, which won our team a number of prizes. Although I didn&rsquo;t qualify for the job, I met a number of friends, whom I would later meet again in New York. A few months later, I would reach out to these friends and teach a class with Ada and Ryan.</p>

<p>In returning to California, I believed I would live at my parents home while going to community colleges to finish my last semester of Chinese requirements. Instead, upon the week school was set to start, I realized I had enrolled in classes beneath my grade level and needed to make an executive decision: Would I wait one more semester before finishing my class or would I do what was necessary to finalize my credits. I decided that Monday, I would move to New York and proceed with the college I had previously decided was too expensive. I bought my ticket to New York for the next day and packed what I needed into a small backpack. I found a place to sleep on AirBNB, where I eventually stayed for over a month.</p>

<p>I absolutely wouldn&rsquo;t have been able to make the move without the help of my mother. In the beginning of January, I believed I was staying in Orange County, so I expended my savings through traveling. After deciding to move to New York, I had much less money than I would need to find an apartment. My mother leant me approximately four thousand dollars of her personal savings so I could enroll in school. As a result of her financial support, everything that followed was made possible.</p>

<h2>February</h2>

<p>February was the first full month I was in New York. The apartment I found on AirBNB was in Brooklyn and my school was in Queens. Initially, I didn&rsquo;t realized how difficult it was to get between the two, but later I would realize it is one of the worst commutes in the city. From the day I arrived, I bussed to Queens college everyday to sort out my class registration and student enrollment. Coincidentally and fortunately, I was able to enroll in classes that took place only on the weekends. As a result, I would have the whole week open to working a regular job.</p>

<p>I got settled with work as soon as possible. I started looking for full-time jobs through recruiters and quickly found myself contract over Craigslist. Ironically, I worked with the city of Anaheim and Oceanside, which were both from the county I had left in San Francisco. I also started contracts in the local area with Metamorphis Day Spa.</p>

<p>I flex back and forth to California a few times during February. For one, I spoke at the Soka Education Conference. The process for writing a paper was excruciating and significantly delayed. Having been able to present will be one of my golden memories. In the midst of getting settled in New York and having returned back to the US, I was able to synthesize a presentation on educational technologies and distributed classrooms.</p>

<p>Once returning back to NY, the second recruiter I spoke with was promising. Aquent&rsquo;s staff was incredibly helpful and supportive of my job search. I had a strict condition of 50$ an hour and full-time work, which the previous recruiter did not think was possible. Brad found me a great position with Acquinity Interactive. For the period while I was in school, Acquinity was exactly what I needed, but the company was very odd from the beginning.</p>

<h2>March</h2>

<p>February was a rush of settling at school and work. By March, I realized my classes were above my level. The topics of class were for Chinese national Chinese majors in the United States. I was the only caucasian english speaker. I knew I wouldn&rsquo;t pass unless I had some help. Taking Jihii&rsquo;s recommendation, I found a tutor. The classes I took were almost completely full of native Chinese speakers. I checked craigslist and asked classmates until for a Chinese tutor, until I decided on Fei. He was a mid-40&rsquo;s Chinese project manger who lived in Queens. I ended up seeing Fei every other night for nearly three months. We met at Starbucks or Pret after we both got out of work. The routine was work-tutor on Monday through Friday and school-school on the weekends.</p>

<p>In March, Aquent asked me to teach a class on web development. They offered to pay be $250, so I decided to do the class alongside some other people. I asked Ada and Ryan to join me. The session had approximately 20 students. I prepared a Mindnode graphic that we used for referential material. Ada talked about UX, Ryan talked about his experience, and I gave a broad overview.</p>

<p>I kept in touch with LessonOverflow folks. I moved into Flo&rsquo;s old apartment. Heidi and Jean came to visit in New York. It was the beginning of my friendship with Marc.</p>

<h2>April</h2>

<p>By April, I was restless with routine. I felt work was pretty straight forward and school was on track. I began researching Meetups and organizations I could join. My search resulted in the CodeForAmerica civic movement. I met Chris at a data visualization meetup and later started working on what was his idea: govSee. govSee was my first exposure to open projects that leverage public data to increase transparency of government.</p>

<p>I started solving harder problems at work, but I was also meeting people from Govlab. I connected with Joel and Nathan at the Experiment, the NYU hackathon. The event which was made possible through Chris&rsquo;s introduction gave me a foot in the door with various civic heads. I met with Claudia and Cosmo, as well as other regulars at civic tech events.</p>

<p>In April I also met Wayne in a bar and started discussions about Pace.</p>

<h2>May</h2>

<p>The final stretch for classes emerged. In the same month, Marc and I found a new apartment and moved into our current place. I started connecting with Nate and began my Soka Group activities.</p>

<p>I continued participating with the civic tech folk in the facebook hackathon. Aiden, Christopher and Aaron. Good people. Around this time, I also shared my first taxi with a stranger and made a good friend.</p>

<p>Finishing school was my priority. During this time, I became closer with Queens classmates, but largely focused on getting what I needed to get done. Between moving, work and school, I was relieved to have finally settled.</p>

<p>I attended many meetups at Pivotal. I met folks like Mark and started to pursue interest in Ruby. Until then, I declared myself a front-end specialist with ability in PHP. From that point, I started to become much more engaged in becoming well rounded in multiple languages.</p>

<h2>June</h2>

<p>School was finished and began personal pursuits. I enrolled in the ITP camp and experimented with hardware hacking. I got hooked up with Arduino&rsquo;s, Raspberry pis, 3d printing, multicopters, projection mapping, and other physical multimedia projects. I met Amy as well as decided to attend Games for Change. I taught a class on Git while there.</p>

<p>My contract at Acquinity expired and I decided on going to Ecuador and Peru with Ryan, Jenn, Leia to meet Miles and Devan. Within the SGI, we had the &ldquo;family fun festival&rdquo; as well as finished the academy battle. By the end of June, I was starting back in to the rhythm I would finish off the year.</p>

<p>I started working with AdsYolo. AdsYolo felt like an off spent contract for the company. The contract was exemplary of lack of communication and structure. The &ldquo;blue skies&rdquo; project that was their website resulted in what I assume to be a dissatisfied outcome for the C-level folk. Looking back now, the only work that stood was the logo I made. Good show.</p>

<p>I also officially incorporated A Triangle Corporation as a Delaware based entity. This was paper work filed, but also a big step in regards to official operations.</p>

<h2>July</h2>

<p>I flew to Ecuador and spent two weeks in utter amazement. I started the trip with feeling kidnapped. I was invited to paint a mural that got on national news. We went on volcano hikes, pouring rain walks, and random strolls through Quito. We eventually rented a car and drove through the Andes mountains to Peru. Between the border, mechanical issues, driving all day, and occasional pitstops, we finally made it into Peru. Meeting Miles and Devan in Peru was the icing on the cake. Guiayusa, roof top &ldquo;alarm systems&rdquo;, the scratched up car paint&hellip;</p>

<p>While in Ecuador, I also put together the NYU govlab prototype. Attended some distance lunch-ins. Upon getting back, I continued to freelance and closed up work with AdsYolo. I moved onto the clients with Imagio and Bullett. I busy on a weekly basis. I didn&rsquo;t have one week that I wasn&rsquo;t booked for my full week rate, but I began to feel the sense of insecurity.</p>

<p>I had scheduled a trip to Germany with Ariel, but I decided to cancel it. I was asked to attend the North American Study Conference in August and decided to attend instead. I forfeited a number of plane tickets. When Mike asked me about attending, I knew the dates overlapped, but I decided to attend.</p>

<h2>August</h2>

<p>I decided to find full-time employment. Between the contracts with Julian, I felt the lack of control that came with finding contracts. You are at the will of other people&rsquo;s payment schedule. Unless you instill strong requirements and structure, it is easy to get taken advantage of. I can proudly say that I never had an issue.</p>

<p>I attended the North American Study Conference in Santa Monica. My birthday was celebrated on the first day at the conference. I clearly remember doing gongyo on the main stage. I felt this was my greatest pride. I saw my parents briefly that Sunday and a number of SUA alumni.</p>

<p>Steven, Marc, and Brian, received their gohonzons. Marc&rsquo;s life has been a total inspiration to me. Eventually, he would help Sharon start her own practice.</p>

<p>By August, I was working with Bullett. The relationship with Ryan from GOOD came full circle. He connected me to Busra and everything else is good news. Bullett contracted me to redo their store and eventually their agency site. The project was a pleasure to work with Jack, Ben, Idil, Ayhan, and everyone else. Bullett taught me the importance of customer service above all. Its SO important to clear up any mistakes.</p>

<p>By mid month, I was offered two jobs. One with the UN consulting firm CSF, through Adriana and the Conde Nast job I decided to take. I had strict salary expectations and resulted in being extremely satisfied with the receiving result. Having taken on contracts with Bullett, I decided to accept the job, but begin in September.</p>

<p>I also met my Cousin, Louis, for the first time.</p>

<h2>September</h2>

<p>I finished up with Bullett and I went to Germany on a whim to attend JSConf and CSSConf EU. Im indebted to the free ticket I received from  I met brilliant people whom I feel fortunate to know. It is my honor to be able to see the development of the bleeding edge industry of web technologies.</p>

<p>I also started a contract with the Long Island cable company, CableVision. The contract later fizzled out. The job was an example of too few hours devoted to great of a project. This was the first project that I was assigned but couldn&rsquo;t fulfill to the desired outcome of a client. The communication was horrible and the final product wasn&rsquo;t anywhere needed. The outcome was the result of too much paper work and a looming deadline. The outcome put the Cablevision people in a bad position. In best wishes, I was able to find another developer, who I believe to have accepted the project.</p>

<p>I made a quick stop in San Francisco. I saw Raimi, Whitney, and Juju. I also had dinner with Kenzo. This was the first time I decided to stay in AirBNB places instead of with friends. I attended Twiliocon, which was great, but not my personal interest. I decided my time was better spent visiting with friends. Coincidentally, I ran into a Twilio employee who was the person who interviewed me at a Voxy. That didn&rsquo;t work out, but for the better.</p>

<p>In the last week, I started my first job at Conde Nast.</p>

<h2>October</h2>

<p>The job was exactly what I wanted. The company is amazing, the people working their are brilliant, and the corporation is well recognized. I feel incredibly proud to have the opportunity to grow and develop here. While I am contacted by a number of recruiters, it is my pride to be confident that I have no desire to go anywhere else. I expect to be at Conde for a number of years. I hope to develop alongside my coworkers and see difficult problems to solve.</p>

<p>October was my first full month of employment. I started deepening my understanding of the Conde Nast brand operations. I also began tightening my belt to understand what my role would be. I found the problems to be difficult, but not overwhelming. I found the challenges to be new, but not out of reach. I found my coworkers to be pleasant, but serious. This job is my fortune.</p>

<p>I spent Saturdays at an NYU continuation class. The topic was Advanced Javascript by Aiden.</p>

<h2>November</h2>

<p>The campaign for 3000 youth ended its first part with a huge victory. I met a number of new people through doing shakabuku. I felt pride to support the Harlem Heights region activities.</p>

<p>Marc and I attended FNCC together. Having gone through the challenges up to that point, this didn&rsquo;t feel monumental. Looking back now, this was a golden memory. Immediately after November 8th, the challenge was to reconnect with SGI members. After the excitement, it was important to reflect on the victories and &ldquo;turn the ship&rdquo;.</p>

<p>In the end of the month, I visited my parents. I spent my mothers birthday with her this year. The ability to spend time with my parents is something that I continue to enjoy.</p>

<h2>December</h2>

<p>The month was a series of deadlines at work. The challenges seem small compared to the overwhelming number of challenges in other parts of my life. I look forward to the challenges to come.</p>

<p>I reconnected with the Citymission people from the Govlab events. I decided to finish the project under a kickstart copy.</p>

<p>My father came to visit in New York. We spent time together and then went to visit my grand mother in North Carolina. The trip was the first time I saw GJ in years. The time I spent there was largely oriented around working, but she was incredibly happy to have my father and I visit.</p>

<p>With the year coming to an end, I feel absolutely victorious. This next year will be start of many projects, books, and endeavors.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using the internet to increase business referrals]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/10/07/using-the-internet-to-increase-business-referrals/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-07T21:28:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/10/07/using-the-internet-to-increase-business-referrals</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Internet for lead generation</h1>

<p>There&rsquo;s a number of ways you can increase business through the Internet. One effective approach is to target certain websites or services as platforms for advertising. Another method is to compete for search engine keywords by generating keyword rich content on your website. Lastly, you post your company on the variety of directory websites that display professional services. Each option has it&rsquo;s own benefits and can/should be used in tandem with one another.</p>

<p>Each method has its&#8217; own cost/benefit and area of efficacy. Depending on your strategy, you will invest time or money. In areas that cost money, you will look for the lowest cost for acquiring a customer. Of you spend time, you will want to maximize the benefit of what you do.</p>

<h1>Online advertising</h1>

<p>For advertising, you typically pay for a number of impressions. The goal of any advertising campaign is to find a high number of relevant viewers. In the case of online advertising, relevancy means geographic location and customer need. Your advertising provider will sell you inventory based on keywords on pages. For example, google will sell you advertisements on google products when your selected advertisement display criteria are displayed on a page.</p>

<p>Of course, because there is limited inventory for advertisements, the higher demand advertisements cost higher. High demand keywords are more expensive than unusual keywords. Think of it as displaying a billboard on a busy street, verses a rural driveway.</p>

<p>The Internet is different in that high demand keywords are not always most favorable for you. You may think &ldquo;Los Angeles psychiatry&rdquo; is the best keyword for you. It contains both geographic and topic relevance. The obvious match makes it a high demand keyword set and consequently expensive target.</p>

<h2>Selecting keywords</h2>

<p>For cost-effective advertising, you need to think like your customer. If advertising on a search engine, rather than selecting the obvious keyword match, target something your customer would type. This can be a question, sentence or fragmented thought. By targeted more words, your ad will come up less and consequently cost less. Similarly, your audience will be specific enough that they are typing exactly what you are targeting. Some example targets may be &ldquo;I&rsquo;m feeling depressed about (enter a topic)&rdquo;, &ldquo;who do I talk to about my middle school (choose a incident)&rdquo;, or &ldquo;sad related personal support&rdquo;. The goal is to indirectly target your audience through insight that you can infer.</p>

<p>You must be wondering where to purchase these advertisements or where the advertisement lead. In general, google&rsquo;s Adwords program is a safe place to experiment. Just google Adwords and it will link you to the process. Adwords let you target audiences through setting keywords and determining what regional areas will display your advertisements. The regions are targeted by IP addresses and are generally correct.</p>

<h2>Targeting online destinations</h2>

<p>Another route is to look at specific websites you believe your target demographic uses. This could be a forum, web application, log, or news source. Platforms like these will have a specific area on their site to advertise. From there, you often pay to have your banner or link displayed for a set period of time. Again, like the keywords, it&rsquo;s best to target places that are indirectly related to your audience. The advertisements you purchase will run for a week/month/etc. the advertisement host should have some details regarding the potential audience&rsquo;s demographic.</p>

<p>Back to the other part of the question, where do these advertisements lead to? Rather than squeezing all your contact information and a catch phrase into a small space, you will display advertisements with some &ldquo;hook&rdquo; and a link to a webpage you set. Often this page should be a landing page in your website. This lets you display a specific message to the advertisement leadvertisements, as well as offer access to other resources that may convince them to contact you.</p>

<h3>Landing pages</h3>

<p>Landing pages are very typical. They contain: a short sentence selling the customer, a short contact form, a few details about your services, a set of testimonials, and another contact form. These pages have been heavily tested for efficacy, so there&rsquo;s no need for creating a new method.</p>

<h3>Analytics</h3>

<p>When running any campaign, it&rsquo;s also good practice to measure the traffic on your site. This is the field of web analytics. There are numerous free products that allow you to gain rich insight into your
your websites visitors.</p>

<h1>Search engine optimization</h1>

<p>In addition to advertising, you can focus on generating search engine traffic. This is a natural process that can generate massive traffic. The method is similar to keyword targeted advertisements. The difference is that you generate content on your website that will trigger search engines to display your website for targeted keywords.</p>

<h2>Content generation</h2>

<p>Specifically, this requires you to be doing some kind of writing that is posted on your website. The writing can be in the form of blog posts that review topics your audience may be searching about. The key is to write in a way that makes search engines easily associate your content to your desired keyword. To do this, you focus on writing semantic articles that have marked up headings with you keywords. In addition, the article piece Gould naturally repeat the target keyword multiple time. This may seem like an impediment to the wrong process, but it is relatively normal on most Internet writing.</p>

<h2>Rich data attributes</h2>

<p>In addition to generating content, you can configure your existing site to leverage any rich attributes that search engines may look for in a webpage. Rich attributes are marked up pieces of information that may be displayed in a search result. Examples are author names, addresses, business hours, site maps, and other information. Some search engines, also reward users for being loyal to their services. For instance, displaying a Google+ account on your website&rsquo;s pages will increase your search ranking.</p>

<p>The goal for optimizing search engine visibility is to help make a robot understand the content of your webpage. The search engines goal is to display the most appropriate search results for any keywords. One major part is the existence of relevant content. The next important part is inbound links from other websites. In particular, the links need to come from resources that are associated to your websites topic. By having inbound links from relevant sources, search engines can effectively perceive your website&rsquo;s topic.</p>

<h1>Listing in professional directories</h1>

<p>Lastly, you can also list yourself on a variety of professional services directory websites. This includes, but is no where limited to, websites like Yelp.com, YellowPages, Craigslist or whatever other sites come up when you do general searches for professionals in your field. The key on these sites are to have your existing customers write positive feedback. The Internet is designed to reward people with higher ratings, rarer than give fresh people an opportunity for exposure. In other words, there are many people on directory websites or service listing websites that get very little attention. Rather a small group of people get a majority of the traffic through the juxtaposition of being positively rated. Having 3-6 ratings can make all the difference.</p>

<p>The sites that are most effective for you to list will often require you to register and submit company descriptions. To expedite your registration process, identify what is commonly required (business name, description, services offered, hours of operation, location, etc) and have them in a document to copy and paste. This will let you expedite the registration process. Keep in mind, many of these I recorded are under operation from very few individuals, so you will need to resolve issues yourself.</p>

<p>There are endless more means for utilizing modern media to drive business traffic. The three points I mentioned are the most general. I hope that helps and let me know if you have any more questions!!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Meeting Strangers]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/06/15/on-meeting-strangers/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-15T13:23:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/06/15/on-meeting-strangers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>On meeting strangers</h1>

<p>You should be meeting more strangers. Strangers are scary, smelly, often have lopsided feet, and more than anything, have a lot to offer you. Whether you are sitting on a bus, picking up your mail, getting a cup of coffee, or sitting in your house watching TV while secretly watching what you neighbors do, the strangers in your life have a lot to offer you.])</p>

<h2>Talk to everyone and anyone.</h2>

<p>I mean everyone. You would be very surprised how much the people you casually talk to can offer you exactly what you need. Once you talk to your first stranger, you will be on your way to learning more about the world. Through talking to strangers, you can learn about different careers, life struggles, current events, and occasionally a new cookie recipe. When your standing in line for groceries, getting a cup of your favorite drink, or sitting alone quietly. You can simply start a conversation with &ldquo;hello, my name is _____&rdquo; (please don&rsquo;t actually say &lsquo;underscore-underscore-underscore-underscore&#8221;. Fill in your name instead). Another effective method is joining conversations that have nothing to do with you. While you feel like this is totally unacceptable and disrespectful (it mostly is), occasionally its a great way to get past all the awkward conversation and get straight to the point (&ldquo;I love chocolate chip bacon covered whiskey dipped cookies too!&rdquo;) From there you can take the conversation anywhere.</p>

<h2>Break all the ice.</h2>

<p>Global warm that shit. Start by being as intrusive as possible, so as to learn about the persons personal life. The sooner you can break the ice, the sooner you can have a new friend. Don&rsquo;t worry that you don&rsquo;t know anything about this person. Did you hear a word that sounds vaguely interesting? Does the person have really well hemmed pants? Maybe you want to know whats in the bag they are carrying (&ldquo;So whats in the bag?&rdquo;). Take them off guard with a question they wouldn&rsquo;t expect from a stranger. Find a commonality and make some personal association to its relationship to you. (&ldquo;Nice novel on ax murdering. I love ax murderingâ€¦&rdquo;).</p>

<h2>Make it easy to get in touch.</h2>

<p>Get a business card. Have a portfolio website to show off. Make your twitter handle easy to pronounce. Stop using that email address you made in 2001 and make something that doesn&rsquo;t have the . By talking to strangers and asking them what they do, you will naturally start up a conversation. (Unless you just creep the person out and need to run away out of fear. If you run away, don&rsquo;t worry. They can&rsquo;t judge you because they are still trying to figure out what just happened.)</p>

<p>But seriously. Go talk to a stranger. Go make friends with someone on the street. Jump in a taxi with someone, even if you&rsquo;re not trying to go anywhere. And start making friends.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On learning from code examples]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/06/01/on-learning-from-code-examples/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-01T09:37:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/06/01/on-learning-from-code-examples</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have developed a four step process to help me learn from coding blogs. There seems to be an endless number of programmers who enjoy sharing their software development discoveries in blog posts and articles. I often find these very informative, although not always well written. Sometimes there is (what seems like) a missing part or gap. I find that the core concepts are discussed, but the directions seem to miss explaining how to get &ldquo;there&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Although instructions are not present, I find that code examples are numerous. Specifically, code examples without explanation behind their inner-workings or core-concepts. As a result, I started pragmatically reviewing the code myself. I use the code examples that are completely foreign to me, to begin a process of exploration and discovery. I have documented this process with examples for readers.</p>

<h1>Step -1: Always be coding</h1>

<p>I find the best way to solve a problem is by having a contextual and relevant application. Without the relevance, you won&rsquo;t be able to remember the problem. You might forget the idea, but you won&rsquo;t be able to apply what you learned when the same problem appears out of context. I find the problems I understand best are the ones I learn to solve when encountered during actual development. This is one of the reasons side-projects are crucial. <strong>Always be coding</strong> and you will always be learning.</p>

<h1>Step 0: Identify well written articles and dependable educational resources</h1>

<p>There are literally hundreds of email newsletters that compile the &ldquo;best&rdquo; articles of development in your field. I get no less than 10 a week. Some of languages I feel overly confident about and others that I am only just starting to learn. Regular exposure to newsletters, as well as online coding communities (such as <a href="http://reddit.com/r/webdev" title="Reddits webdev community">Reddit/r/webdev</a> or HackerNews) will keep you exposed to the well written articles and best educational resources available.</p>

<p>My personal favorite for front-end questions is the Mozilla Development Network (MDN). The MDN has the best documentation on all web related APIs. This means anything you want to learn about HTML5, CSS3, Javascript and web APIs are well documented here. To discover these resources, you can use Google. Simply add the string &ldquo;MDN&rdquo; to a search query and you will find the relevant resources</p>

<p>Using Twitter and Github to follow well known developers has been priceless. Whenever I find an article I enjoy, I follow the authors twitter account (This is a great time for me to say &ldquo;<a href="http://twitter.com/lkbcc" title="Twitter link to @Lkbcc">Follow me on Twitter @Lkbcc</a>&rdquo;). By following developers, you can see what links are being shared and most importantly who they follow. The twitter feeds of developers, open source projects and companies are often the best place for discovery.</p>

<h1>Step 1: Place your browser beside a note taking application</h1>

<p><img src="http://lkb.cc/images/20130601-1-notes-and-browser.jpg" title="Taking notes on an article using Notational Velocity" alt="Screenshot of Chrome web browser beside Notational Velocity note taking application" /></p>

<p>Open up a code editor or note taking application and open it side-by-side your browser window. You are going to write down every idea/snippet/word that you don&rsquo;t understand. This is crucial. Being aware of what you don&rsquo;t know will allow you to advance. It may be painful to realize you read a paragraph, only to write down nearly every word in your notes, but this is where you can start moving forward.</p>

<p>You picked an article with an interesting but difficult topic and lines-on-lines of coding examples. You are about to learn some thing new. Be confident that you can learn this idea, even if it seems completely out of reach. Most of programming is not about being smart, but pushing through the foreign ideas until it &ldquo;clicks&rdquo;. Just as Woody Alan says, &ldquo;Showing up is half the battle&rdquo;. Seriously, just read through the stuff you don&rsquo;t understand, and the exposure to the foreign ideas will be hugely beneficial.</p>

<p>For note taking, I use a program called Notational Velocity. Its a very simple application that makes all my notes easily searchable. I&rsquo;ve seen people effectively use Evernote, TextEdit, and even Word Processors. I find the most important thing is reducing the friction to start the note taking process. I like Notational Velocity because it natively binds a keyboard shortcut to pull up/hide the editor. This process can actually be assigned to any application through a computer&rsquo;s System Preferences.</p>

<h1>Step 2: Copy down code examples. Write them out again from memory</h1>

<p>When you read articles, if you <em>just</em> read the articles, they won&rsquo;t do sit nicely in your head. Like a poorly written Backbone application, you&rsquo;ll have a memory leak, until all the time you took to learn will be forgotten. The best way to remember is to physically go through the code and write it down. If I learned anything from Zed Shaw in his Learning Python the Hard Way, it was the value of copying code.</p>

<p>Often, you will get into the flow of copying/writing out code, without being conscious. Other times, you will be conscious of how impossibly terse a code block is and will not understand it. This is okay. At times, I physically write out code blocks with pen and paper, because it forces me to slow down. Regardless of how you do it, the next part is very important.</p>

<p><img src="http://lkb.cc/images/20130601-2-browser-and-code.jpg" title="Writing out code blocks in Sublime Text 3" alt="Writing out code blocks in Sublime Text 3" /></p>

<p>Write out the previously copied code purely from memory. You can do it write underneath the copied code or in a new page or document. The exercise will force you to be present. No copying aloud. You should go back as needed and look at the original code to jump your memory, but the purpose of this important step is honestly reflecting on what you don&rsquo;t know.</p>

<p>The hardest part of learning to code for me is stubbornness. I either like to default to assuming something is too hard to understand or make believe that I don&rsquo;t need to know an idea. I almost always find myself encountering the same problem or code concepts without fully committing time to understanding them. Don&rsquo;t do this. But sometimes you can write something from memory and still not understand it.</p>

<h1>Step 3: Write out directions to write the previous code</h1>

<p><img src="http://lkb.cc/images/20130601-3-code-instructions.jpg" title="Second iteration of describing the original code example" alt="Second iteration of describing the original code example" /></p>

<p>Next, write out english sentences that tell you exactly what each line of code does. You need to be clear enough that reading these sentences will allow you to understand how to recreate the original lines of code. Do this without giving yourself specific coding syntax. If possible, use the vocabulary to properly describe the code. If you don&rsquo;t know the vocabulary, then its good to check out places like the MDN to review.</p>

<p>This may be weird because you just effectively &ldquo;memorized&rdquo; the previous snippet. A proven effective method of learning is to teach what you know. In the context of coding, you can teach yourself. By treating yourself as both the teacher and student, you can deepen your ability to communicate the coding concepts. Your success in this step will be seen when able to use the instructions to recreate the exact same code as the original code block.</p>

<h1>Step 4: Recreate the original code using your instructions</h1>

<p>Using your instructions, attempt to write out the original block of code. Be strict with yourself and follow your instructions. Don&rsquo;t pull from your memory (Assume an irreversible memory leak). Go through your instructions, and line-by-line try to write what you communicated to yourself.</p>

<pre><code>// Example for completed description
// define function called getHTTPObject
// check if XMLHttpRequest exists
// if it does return it as a constructor
// otherwise try to return the constructor for ActiveXObject with Msxml2.XMLHTTP attribute
// check for errors
// and if they come up try to return a constructor for ActiveXObject with Microsoft.XMLHTTP attribute
// check for errors again and kill the process
// After the original conditional, return false

function getHTTPObject(){
  if (typeof XMLHttpRequest != "undefined"){
    return new XMLHttpRequest;
  } 
  try {
    return new ActiveXObject("Msxml2.XMLHTTP")
  } catch (e) {
    try {
      return new ActiveXObject("Microsoft.XMLHTTP")
    } catch (e) {}
  }
  return false;
}
</code></pre>

<p>If you do anything like me, then your initial instructions are going to suck. Through this forced consciousness process, you will notice parts that you either missed or didn&rsquo;t understand enough to explain. Review the actual code and try to revisit your instructions again.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s important that during this process, you are not looking at the code while writing the instructions. As much as possible, try to understand the idea, move away from the original, then document your understanding. This is maximize your opportunity to discover where you don&rsquo;t understand.</p>

<h1>Step 5: There is no step 5</h1>

<p><img src="http://lkb.cc/images/20130601-4-code-success.jpg" title="Code cat success" alt="Code cat success" /></p>

<p>You have iterated this process enough to accomplish your end goal of writing instructions that clearly explain the code, you will have accomplished one of two things: mindlessly memorized completely useless code, or remembered the syntax/framework/structure of some code which you don&rsquo;t completely understand.</p>

<p>If you are in the latter, then you&rsquo;re on the right path. You realize that no code is perfect and often your understanding of concepts too is imperfect. More importantly, you realize how to communicate what you know and also provide yourself a mechanism for understand what other people are trying to communicate. You provide yourself a strong tool for learning from the plethora of undocumented, but very useful code.</p>

<p>Hopefully this idea was not new to you and you have now learned an effective way to push yourself to learn new coding concepts. Take notes, copy down code examples, give yourself instructions to rewrite the examples, and most importantly look up all the questions you have!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA["Failing into the pit of success"]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/06/01/failing-into-the-pit-of-success/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-01T09:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/06/01/failing-into-the-pit-of-success</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Why learn?</h1>

<p>I have spent the past three years developing websites. I have been hired by clients ranging from startups to fortune 500 corporations. Yet, I don&rsquo;t have any formal training as a computer scientist or digital designer. I went to school to study in a Liberal Arts program in the humanities. I read books on cultural theory, history, and adopted an obscure love for classical literature (Goethe I&rsquo;m looking at you).</p>

<p>So why does this all matter? Well, like most people, I wanted to get on the band wagon of utilizing the immense power available today in the form of technology. I saw computers as the beginning, but instantly knew before smart phones that mobile technologies were offering amazing opportunities through widely distributed data networks. I wanted to use this, but I didn&rsquo;t have any training. I think a lot of people around my age (and those who are not) have this feeling.</p>

<p>I started learning web development, and more recently Javascript. Javascript was my &ldquo;in&rdquo; to the growing digital frontier. Making a website was foreign to me, but I found people would pay me to do it, so I invested my time to get good at it. I identified the front-end (User Experience, User facing elements, Design) web development as most interesting to me.</p>

<h1>Deciding the front-end</h1>

<p>Deciding I would become prolific at front-end technologies (HTML/CSS/Javascript), I found myself struggling with the abstract concepts of Javascript. I also noticed that Javascript could potentially offer the most learning value. As the founder of Javascript says, &ldquo;Always bet on Javascript&rdquo;.</p>

<p>I traverse the infinitum of blog posts being written on software engineering to find the rare nuggets of informative learning resources. I find myself attracted by titles to blog posts, but unable to comprehend the complex code blocks. Instead, I browse the (often Jekyll or Octopress) blog posts, only to read the commentary and skip of the code segments.</p>

<p>My greatest obstacle when reading code is that I&rsquo;m feeling like I understand the code, but fail to absorb the lessons. Overcoming the mammoth that is learning to code by adopting good practices has significantly helped. I can confidently say, I am not good at learning over the internet or even teaching myself how to do &ldquo;stuff&rdquo;. Instead, I am good at identifying my faults in remembering and make up for it by creating processes that make me &ldquo;fail forward&rdquo;.</p>

<p>I know that I fail at absorbing coding concepts. I also know that I am good at learning from mistakes. I combine the two understandings about myself by forming a practice to force myself to fail at absorbing coding concepts by making guided mistakes. I do this without another teacher guiding me or a tutor.</p>

<p>Note: The term &ldquo;Failing into the pit of success&rdquo; was a term developed by a software developer at Microsoft.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MacArthur Facebook Posh Hackathon recap]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/05/09/macarthur-facebook-posh-hackathon-recap/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T22:50:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/05/09/macarthur-facebook-posh-hackathon-recap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I created AdGoggles for the Facebook-MacArthur foundation hackathon. The event was a wonderfully organized event by the Chelsea Pier in the 585 Art gallery complex. Amazing food, the highest of quality attendees, and amazing prizes.</p>

<h2>Advertisement Goggles</h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Freelance talent tracking: A proposal]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/05/02/freelance-talent-tracking-a-proposal/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-02T16:37:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/05/02/freelance-talent-tracking-a-proposal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/eqrzumY.jpg" alt="The dashboard full of ads" /></p>

<p>Freelancers miss sales opportunities due to time traveling and poor coordination. Once we have production on the first DeLorean is complete, this will no longer be an issue. Until then, talent with GPS devices can broadcast their travel itinerary to acquire clients on the go.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jason Goldberg at NYU Startup Week Keynote]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/04/10/jason-golberg-at-nyu-startup-weeek-keynote/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-10T10:21:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/04/10/jason-golberg-at-nyu-startup-weeek-keynote</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Upcoming blog post about professional WordPress development and some of the tools that can help your workflow. Also, I&rsquo;ll start writing a weekly article on how to learn Javascript. A few of the upcoming articles will be about Test Driven Development, using jQuery, common Javascript design patterns, as well as many more.</em></p>

<h1>Fab.com CEO Jason Goldberg</h1>

<p>Jason Goldberg came to NYU&rsquo;s Startup week this week to speak with <a href="http://penenberg.com/">Adam Penenberg</a>. Penenberg led Goldberg through his entrepreneurial path from college dropout to CEO. Goldberg&rsquo;s success and ongoing journey encourages eager adventurers like myself. A few points from Goldberg:</p>

<ol>
<li>It&rsquo;s worth pursuing what you believe is meaningful, even if it means dropping out of school (twice).</li>
<li>Find the one thing you are particularly good at and focus on it.</li>
<li>Find a partner who you admire.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t outsource. Make partnerships.</li>
<li>Invest in customers, rather than short-term revenue.</li>
</ol>


<h2>It&rsquo;s worth pursuing what you believe is meaningful, even if it means dropping out of school (twice).</h2>

<p>Goldberg was born in Rockville, Maryland (followed by a single cheer in the audience) and went Emeryville for his bachelors degree. He dropped out of college in 91&#8217; to work on Bill Clintons presidential campaign. Believed in Clinton before he was the Democratic nominee, but saw the potential behind Clinton&rsquo;s cause. His first volunteer position was to &ldquo;drive around the wife&rdquo; when she came to visit Atlanta. Ended up spending six and a half years in the Whitehouse in the economic council with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Erskine_Bowles#The_Clinton_years">Erskine Bowles</a>. By 1998, he was a completely different person (joking about weighing 185 pounds) and worked 7 days a week.</p>

<p>To take a break, he decided to go to business school at Stanford. While at Stanford, received a call from Bowles under the lines of (cue southern drawl) &ldquo;I just put 50 million dollars in a company, but don&rsquo;t know what they do. Can you find out for me?&rdquo;. Left Stanford mid-degree to join the startup Bowles invested into and began the startup culture of the dot-com era. This is where he saw excess and understood the importance of a business model. He also learned this is where you invest in people that you know.</p>

<p>Following the dot com bubble&rsquo;s burst, he moved to AOL Time Warner, right after the merger. He did strategy work but knew he was more interested in operations and management. He also knew that he was much more focused on user experience and moved to T-Mobile, where he worked on their first hotspot network. This was his first &ldquo;big win&rdquo; in his career. After finishing his project, the T-mobile CEO said &ldquo;you can do whatever you want&rdquo;. Shortly after, Goldberg pursued his own company.</p>

<h2>Find the one thing you are particularly good at and focus on it.</h2>

<p>For Goldberg, he knew his talent was in User Experience. Rather than being stuck micromanaging every part of his own company, he wanted to focus on the part that he knew best. His past projects were always recognized comparatively as the best user experiences. Rather than being caught up in all parts of the business, he wanted to lead the thing he knew best: User Experience. This is exactly what he did.</p>

<p>Goldberg&rsquo;s first company in 2003 was a job-centered social network called Jobster. He noticed that the best hires at his companies were the friends of existing effective employees. Jobster was mean to help hiring &ldquo;someone who knew someone who knew someone else&rdquo;. The idea that good people knew good people that you should hire, resulted in a social network before its time. LinkedIn, coming a year later, approached the same space through creating a network. Jobster approached it by creating the tools that a company could use to tap a network.</p>

<p>Jobster had good ideas, but Goldberg felt he &ldquo;ran too fast&rdquo;. Instead of focusing on the one thing that he knew he was good at, he was involved in everything else. By doing everything, he got nothing done. Through the process he learned if he started another company, he would focus on being the project manager. Sadly, his next project was with Microsoft developers on a Microsoft development cycle. The one-year development cycle didn&rsquo;t work for the internet.</p>

<p>When Facebook launched, he saw how apps were launching with millions of downloads going viral. Discovering an app making use of the emerging social-graph, he contacted the developers asking to &ldquo;buy your company&rdquo;. He discovered the app was built by two engineers in India and couldn&rsquo;t even keep their servers running because of the traffic they received. As a result, he hired them to work at Jobster and built a product in four weeks that was better than anything the company had built before.</p>

<p>His new product enabled a very simple aggregate of the people in your social network circle. Goldberg related it to Facebook&rsquo;s News Feed, before it existed. The focus was helping people discover news, just the way he was interested in discovering the news. The product was rolling out right before the election cycle and in under a year had several million users. The company sold in fourth quarter to a European social network, Zing.</p>

<h2>Find a partner who you admire.</h2>

<p>Goldberg moved to work in Germany to work on Zing, where he missed his boyfriend. This led him to decide on building a social network for gay men. The idea was developed with Bradford Shellhammer, who Goldberg had met years before outside a nightclub at 2am. Goldberg stayed friends with Shellhammer through mutual respect for one another. He felt Shellhammer was one of the most creative people he has ever met. &ldquo;Bradford brought color to peoples lives.&rdquo; To add, Shellhammer was showcased in Times magazine, twice.</p>

<p>The first idea of Fabulous was well timed with the trend for a new gay culture. Goldberg was confident in building a new product. Fabulous was &ldquo;Gay foursquare meets gay trip advisor meets gay deal of the day&rdquo;. Goldberg saw his relationships with Shellhammer as &ldquo;Im a geek and your a gay&rdquo; so we should do something. He knew he could build an amazing user experience and he had complete faith in the style that Shellhammer would produce.</p>

<p>In 2010, the two decided they would leverage their community to start selling stuff. On paper the idea for Fabulous looked perfect, but it wasn&rsquo;t taking off. The mainstreaming of gay culture made a gay app less needed. Glee, Modern Family, Grindr and all these &ldquo;things&rdquo; started coming up. Goldberg states, &ldquo;even Facebook turned gay&rdquo;. Seeing that the only successful communities were being based around sex, he wan&rsquo;t to shift into selling stuff.</p>

<p>The idea for Fab took off during a dinner with Shellhammer. After three bottles of wine at the Market Village, they decided they were not leaving until they figured out what they were doing next. They liked working together, recognized the unique talents they brought together, and both wanted to work on &ldquo;design&rdquo;. Using Shellhammer&rsquo;s taste, Goldberg suggested &ldquo;lets build a business around your tastes and sensibilities to the world&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Shortly after the decision, they told their Board of Directors a plan to shutdown the existing website and move ahead with their new idea. Note, they had no idea what they were going to do and were clear with their investors that they could step out and get their money back if they wanted.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Internet browsers with Chinese characteristics]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/03/20/internet-browsers-with-chinese-characteristics/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-20T09:46:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/03/20/internet-browsers-with-chinese-characteristics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Being in China</h2>

<p>The ex-patriots in China are very aware of the internet restrictions. Aka, internet with Chinese characteristics. Itâ€™s hard to explain to others what itâ€™s like behind the Great Firewall. No facebook, no NY Times, and the sense of consistency. Beyond the occasional officially-unofficial media blackouts, most of the world doesn&rsquo;t think about what the internet is like in China, even though there are more internet users in China than there are citizens of the United States. <a href="http://j.mp/12wZ7mL">apira.org</a></p>

<p>The censorship is secondary to considerations of the internet for web developers targeting Chinese users. In China, Internet Explorer 6 was king for far too long. The fallout from its history is obvious for web developers from the West. Like myself, China facing websites do not have the luxury of ignoring &ldquo;obsolete&rdquo; users. In a country where there are over 250 million Internet Explorer users, China facing websites consider an incredibly aggressive browser ecosystem.</p>

<h2>Battle against the obsolete</h2>

<p>There have, however, been enormous improvements in browser technologies recently. Two years ago IE6 had a 60% market share in China (<a href="http://j.mp/13HOpZG">w3.org</a>. Today, the wonderful website <a href="http://www.ie6countdown.com/">IE6CountDown</a> states IE6 is a little more than 25% of the Chinese internet user population.</p>

<p>The problem with IE6 is not one of ignorance. IE6â€™s prior domination of the Chinese browser-share was the result of Chinaâ€™s piracy ecosystem. Remember the Windows XP system updates? If you remember correctly, only authorized editions of Windows XP are allowed to make those system updates. Because Chinese street markets sell a lot of &ldquo;low-cost&rdquo; software (aka, pirated software), a lot of Chinese computers canâ€™t get official system updates. Old computers without system updates are unable to upgrade from their original IE6 browser.</p>

<p>Adding insult to injury, Chinese web developers target the IE6 browsers. Jerry Jinks from <a href="http://www.maxthon.com/about-us/">Maxthon</a> (a Chinese web browser provider) elegantly <a href="http://www.w3.org/QA/2012/06/interview_huawei_maxthon_qihoo.html">explained</a> the IE6 problem: &ldquo;There&rsquo;s a vicious cycle around IE6 in China: users keep using it because sites are designed for IE6, and people build sites for IE6 because users stay with it.&rdquo; By having a market that depends on IE6, web developers can continue buildings for obsolete systems. Table based layouts, Dreamweaver WYSIWYG markup, and browser hacks litter Chinese websites.</p>

<p>Although the problem is large, the problem has not gone unaddressed. Microsoft partnered with Chinese anti-virus and internet browser company Qihoo 360 to systematically eliminate IE6. The partnership allowed Qihoo to make upgrades to the default browser on Windows XP systems from IE6 to IE8. Because Qihoo markets itself as a â€œsecurity solution,â€ users recognize the need to download and install the new software. While users feel they are more secure, Qihoo is really just another web browser.</p>

<p>Qihooâ€™s browser is based on a Microsoft browser framework called Trident. Trident, like Webkit, is a rendering engine which allows browser makers to have a solid starting point. Rather than rewriting a complete browser engine, browser developers can start from solid footing to customize the user experience, rather than the rendering engine. For reasons related to Chinaâ€™s interest in Microsoft products, Trident has been very popular.</p>

<p>Two of the largest China based browsers, Qihoo and Maxthon, use Trident (<a href="http://j.mp/15A73RR">sec.gov</a>). Trident was developed by Microsoft to server as a web rendering engine for applications accessing web pages. Trident leverages parts of Internet Explorer, Webkit, and Chrome for various tasks. Interestingly enough, although Trident continues to develop today, the versions in Qihoo and Maxthon are dependent on IE8. Although the Chinese markets are moving off IE6, they are still using IE8. For web developers, that means no media-queries, no CSS3&hellip;</p>

<p>For browser developers, using an existing rendering engines makes sense. The W3C and WHATWG have both been emphasizing the need for browser consistency. After the intensional varriance of Netscape and Internet Explorer in the 90â€™s, browsers started keeping to a set of rules. For new browsers developing, like Qihoo and Maxthon, using existing rendering engines allows the companies to focus on other features. For example, Qihoo focuses on firewall and virus scanning tools. Compared to other alternative browsers, like Chrome and Firefox, marketing based on the value of security has worked in Qihooâ€™s favor.</p>

<h2>Different priorities</h2>

<p>China&rsquo;s web infrastructure growth has impressed me with its high internet penetration rates, but the websites themselves are not so innovative. To be fair to Chinese web developers, though, there is a different focus on developing for the web in China. Users here don&rsquo;t want the newest technologies just because they are available. Again, as <a href="http://www.w3.org/QA/2012/06/interview_huawei_maxthon_qihoo.html">Jerry Jinks stated</a>, &ldquo;They just want to see the Web&rdquo;. The issue is along the expectations behind the Chinese internet consumers. Just because there are a lot of users, does not by any means result in high quality websites.</p>

<p>US web users are spoiled. If a website isnâ€™t pretty or doesn&rsquo;t load in a set period of time, they donâ€™t want to visit the site. There is research that proves this (<a href="http://j.mp/Yf5WRn">seomoz</a>. Chinese users browsing habits are still developing. Standing on a train and looking over people&rsquo;s shoulders, you see people reading websites rendered without any CSS.</p>

<p>Importance is not widely placed on web standards. Beautiful, shiny, CSS3-filled, progressively enhanced HTML5 websites are few in China. In fact, there are some web practices that are simply painful to watch (<a href="http://zombo.com/">queue Flash splash page leading to table layout website</a>). The need for old browser coverage results in the sheer inability to embrace innovative technologies. It doesn&rsquo;t help that new libraries and frameworks are proudly dropping support for IE6 and IE7.
Ironically, in a place where old browsers are such a problem, I have yet to see a Chinese progressively enhance or gracefully degrading website. When Modernizer and polyfills are being developed for the exact purpose of serving the worlds edge case browsers, I don&rsquo;t see a wide range of Chinese adopters.</p>

<p>Thereâ€™s a plethora of digital and printed content about web development available in English, but rarely to I see the same kind of material circulated in China. While I don&rsquo;t know if an internet growth market would be interested in the concepts of web standards, it could benefit from access to the discussions.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>There is something to be said for the recent popularization of dropping support for old browsers. Undeniably, costs to develop for old browsers can be unreasonably high and unmanageable. Still, it should be considered that dropping support for old browsers entails dropping support for huge parts of the world. I am certain that in the coming years, China won&rsquo;t be as affected by this issue. Mobile browsers are exponentially claiming internet browser marketshare. For mobile devices alone, heads are turning toward standards and HTML5.</p>

<p>Until then, don&rsquo;t forget about the products Made in China and good luck finding stylish Chinese system fonts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Basic TileMill: Making Beautiful Maps]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/03/14/basic-tilemill-making-beautiful-maps/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-14T12:57:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/03/14/basic-tilemill-making-beautiful-maps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://forrst-live.s3.amazonaws.com/multiposts/images/39039/mega.png?1363124354" alt="Using TileMill" /></p>

<h1>TileMill makes beautiful maps</h1>

<p><a href="http://mapbox.com/tilemill/">TileMill</a> is a downloadable program that allows you to make beautiful maps. The software is developed by <a href="http://mapbox.com/">MapBox</a>, a company that provides OpenSource maps as a service.</p>

<p>TileMill is a basic GUI for skinning GIS data. Using a CSS like language, called <a href="http://mapbox.com/tilemill/docs/manual/carto/">CartoCSS</a>, users can modify and add visual elements. CartoCSS provides conditional logic, allowing styles to target specific segments of data.</p>

<p>An example of segmented data styling is in open data regarding city populations. Using the CartoCSS, you can render a circle on all of the cities in the world. Using conditional logic, you can make the circle bigger or smaller based on the population of the city.</p>

<h2>Getting started</h2>

<p>To get an introduction to TileMill, I suggest going through the <a href="http://mapbox.com/tilemill/docs/crashcourse/introduction/">Crash Course</a> provided by MapBox. The crash course will show you how to load in external data sets, provide conditional styling, and export your map (or upload it online).</p>

<h2>Quick Lesson</h2>

<p>I <a href="http://forrst.com/posts/Beautiful_maps_with_CSS_and_open_data-FRM">showcased a map</a> I made for Acquinity Interactive on <a href="http://forrst.com">Forrst</a> this week. On it, I showed the working files of the TileMill map I created. One of the users requested that I explain how to make something like this.</p>

<h3>Step 1: Download and install</h3>

<p>I won&rsquo;t go into detail. Get the program <a href="http://mapbox.com/tilemill/">here</a> and install it.</p>

<h3>Step 2: Start a new project</h3>

<p>Click Projects > New project. Set a filename. Make sure the &ldquo;Default data&rdquo; box is check. Then click Add. Click the newly created project to open up the Editor.</p>

<h3>Step 3: Add in open data</h3>

<p>Just as you will learn in the Crash Course I mentioned above, we will add in a new layer of data. For the sake of this example, we will select the urban city data.</p>

<p>Click Add Layer, at the top right. Once the Add layer model pops up, click Browse. In Browse, click MapBox.</p>

<p>Once in MapBox, click to mapbox-geodata / natural-earth-1.4.0 / cultural / 10m-populated-places.zip. Then click done and save.</p>

<h3>Step 4: Find the data to style</h3>

<p>From here, you can style anything from the countries you can see, to the data that you just loaded in. For the sake of simplicity, we will make a selector on the cities we loaded in and differentiate them by population.</p>

<p>For more specific selectors, you can go to the CartoCSS documentation.</p>

<h3>Step 4.5: Code example</h3>

<p>After looking at the Layer&rsquo;s &ldquo;Feature&rdquo; data, I found the data column <strong>POP_MIN</strong> that I would like to target.</p>

<p>The proper syntax for selecting a data attribute is similar to CSS. I will use <code>#10mpopulatedplaces{}</code> to make a selector for the data we imported.</p>

<p>Second, I will made a distinction between the small, medium, and large cities with a conditional selector. The conditional selector should go onsite the one we created above. You can make something like this:</p>

<pre><code>#10mpopulatedplaces {
  marker-width:1;
  marker-fill-opacity: 0;
  marker-line-color:#ec9a14;
  marker-allow-overlap:true;

  [POP_MIN &lt;= 1200000] { marker-width:100;marker-opacity: 0.4; marker-line-width:1.0; }
  [POP_MIN &gt; 1200000]   { marker-width:400; marker-opacity: 0.1; }
  [POP_MIN &gt; 10000000]   { marker-width:700; marker-opacity: 0.5; marker-line-width:.3;}
</code></pre>

<p>This will make three different styles targeting cities with a minimum population smaller than or equal to 1,200,000, larger than 1,200,000 and larger than 10,000,000. The styles that I select are the marker <em>size</em>, <em>opacity</em>, and <em>border</em>. CartoCSS documentation explains there are a number of other styling features such as fill, glow, and much others.</p>

<h3>Step 5: Export</h3>

<p>From here, you have a map with some generic circles. You can make some additional styling choices to the land and ocean. If you want to make the purple map that I had, you can find the style.mss content <a href="https://gist.github.com/lkbgift/5163407">here</a></p>

<p>Go ahead and click Export to get the choices of different export formats. Personally, I like to screenshot the export screen, then modify the screenshot in Photoshop. I have found it looks more like the way I want it to. Otherwise, explore in PNG and set the dimensions.</p>

<h2>Learning More</h2>

<p>The above was a really basic instruction set. This doesn&rsquo;t do justice to the capacity of TileMill, so I highly suggest that you go and follow the Crash Course provided by TileMill and experiment yourself.</p>

<p>If you are interested in digital maps, I highly suggest listening to the <a href="http://5by5.tv/webahead/23">WebAhead podcast on Maps with Alex Barth</a>. This was the first time I learned about TileMill and MapBox.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using multiple icon fonts from Zurb]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/03/11/using-multiple-icon-fonts-from-zurb/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-11T13:31:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/03/11/using-multiple-icon-fonts-from-zurb</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://cdn.css-tricks.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/set-zurb.jpg" alt="Zurb's Foundation Icons" /></p>

<h1>Using multiple icon fonts from Zurb</h1>

<h2>Preface</h2>

<p>The creators of Foundation, Zurb, provide useful tools for full-stack developers. One of their freely available tools are the Icon Fonts found <a href="http://www.zurb.com/playground/foundation-icons">here</a>. The fonts are free. There are four sets: general, enclosed, social, and accessibility.</p>

<p>Of the four sets, it is difficult to simply choose one. Personally, I took a couple icons from each set. Because Zurb sets up their font sets in SASS files, this becomes exceptionally easy.</p>

<p><em>This guide is for users of Foundation and SASS</em></p>

<h2>How to setup</h2>

<h3>1. Download</h3>

<p>First, download the fonts that you want from the Foundation Icons page. The link is here: <a href="http://www.zurb.com/playground/foundation-icons">http://www.zurb.com/playground/foundation-icons</a>.</p>

<h3>2. Moving files</h3>

<p>Second, grab the files located in the <code>/sass</code> and <code>/fonts</code> directory. Move these two directories to your website&rsquo;s main root directory. My home directory is setup like this:</p>

<pre><code>/
/index.html
/css/*.css
/css/*.scss
/css/[ONE-FONT-SET]/[scss-FILES]
/fonts/[FONTS-GO-HERE]
/images/
/scripts/
</code></pre>

<p>I have my SASS files and CSS files in the same directory. I create a separate directory in the <code>/css/</code> directory for each individual font <code>.scss</code> file set. Because I use SASS, I try to keep my working directories as organized as possible. I place the font files (<code>.eot</code>, <code>.svg</code>, <code>.tff</code>, <code>.woff</code>) into the <code>/fonts/</code> directory.</p>

<h3>3. Update Foundation Icon .scss files</h3>

<p>After your files are placed in their respective directories, you need to update the files paths declared in the files. Also, if you are using multiple fonts, then you need to update the CSS class names, so the fonts do not overwrite one another.</p>

<p>First, open the <code>_settings.scss</code> file for each font set. You should have something that looks like this:</p>

<pre><code>$fontFileName: "../fonts/general_foundicons";
$fontName: "GeneralFoundicons";
$classPrefix: "foundicon-";

@mixin i-class($name,$pua) {
  .#{$classPrefix}#{$name}:before { 
    content: "\f#{$pua}";
  }
}

@mixin ie-class($name,$pua) {
  .#{$classPrefix}#{$name} { 
    *zoom: expression( this.runtimeStyle['zoom'] = "1", this.innerHTML = "&amp;#xf#{$pua};"); 
  }
}

@mixin face {
  @font-face { 
    font-family: $fontName;
    src: url('#{$fontFileName}.eot');
    src: url('#{$fontFileName}.eot?#iefix') format('embedded-opentype'),
         url('#{$fontFileName}.woff') format('woff'),
         url('#{$fontFileName}.ttf') format('truetype'),
         url('#{$fontFileName}.svg##{$fontName}') format('svg');
    font-weight: normal;
    font-style: normal;
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>You need to change the first and third lines, respective to your own setup. The first line declares where you font files are located, respective to where you compiled .scss files appear. For me, my CSS files render in <code>/css/*</code>. To access the <code>/fonts/</code> directory, I use <code>../fonts/general_foundicons</code> to go up one directory and into <code>/fonts/</code>.</p>

<p>If you are using multiple fonts, you need to change the <code>$classPrefix</code> statement on the third time of <code>_settings.scss</code> to be unique. I change the name of my General Set from</p>

<pre><code>$classPrefix: "foundicon-";
</code></pre>

<p>to</p>

<pre><code>$classPrefix: "foundicongen-";
</code></pre>

<p>Similarly, I changed my accessibility, social, and enclosed sets respectively, by adding one three letters after <code>foundicon</code>.</p>

<h3>4. Using icons in webpage</h3>

<p>For this part, you can follow the directions on Zurb&rsquo;s instructions. You need to find out the name of the font icon you want to declare. Then, using the <code>&lt;i&gt;</code> tag, set the class <code>foundicon-[icon]</code>, where [icon] is the name of the icon you want to declare.</p>

<p>In my case, because I am using multiple fonts, I needed to rename the class prefix above. Therefore, depending on the icon set I am pulling, I need to declare class that reflects the icon set.</p>

<p>For example, if I want the globe icon from the General Icons set, I will declare:</p>

<pre><code>&lt;i class="foundicongen-globe"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>This will appropriately pull the Globe icon associated with the General Icon set.</p>

<h3>5. Style Away!</h3>

<p>Again, just as the Zurb page says, you can now freely use CSS techniques to manipulate the icons. You can change colors, add triggers (hover, focus, active), as well as set animations using CSS3.</p>

<p>Enjoy!</p>

<p>For any questions, feel free to contact me at <a href="http://twitter.com/lkbcc">@lkbcc</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deploying WordPress with Capistrano symlink issue fix]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/03/04/deploying-wordpress-with-capistrano-symlink-issue-fix/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-04T12:22:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/03/04/deploying-wordpress-with-capistrano-symlink-issue-fix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Fix from &ldquo;<a href="http://theme.fm/2011/08/tutorial-deploying-wordpress-with-capistrano-2082/">Tutorial: Deploying WordPress with Capistrano</a>&rdquo; by <a href="http://theme.fm/author/kovshenin/">Konstantin Kovshenin</a></h1>

<p>I was using the three blog posts by <a href="http://theme.fm/author/kovshenin/">Konstantin Kovshenin</a> about using Capistrano with WordPress. The blog post tutorials were written in 2011.</p>

<p>I kept having issues with the symlink code used in the post. The code looks like this:</p>

<pre><code>namespace :myproject do
    task :symlink, :roles =&gt; :app do
        run "ln -nfs #{shared_path}/uploads #{release_path}/application/wp-content/uploads"
    end
end

after "deploy:symlink", "myproject:symlink" 
</code></pre>

<h2>Problem: Tasks not being executed on <code>cap deploy</code></h2>

<p>Not having a Ruby background, I couldn&rsquo;t easily debug the situation. To keep it short, every time I <code>cap deploy</code> the commands in the <code>:myproject</code> would not execute.</p>

<p>I believe the newest Capistrano no longer uses the <code>"deploy:symlink"</code> as a valid trigger. Therefore, the snippet originally provided was not working.</p>

<h2>Solution: Change trigger</h2>

<p>It&rsquo;s not a fancy outcome, but I changed the line:</p>

<pre><code>after "deploy:symlink", "myproject:symlink"
</code></pre>

<p>to</p>

<pre><code>after "deploy", "myproject:symlink"
</code></pre>

<p>Now my symlink is run correctly and I am able to see my tasks run when I <code>cap deploy</code>.</p>

<p><strong>This is a fix to issues I found in Tutorial: Deploying WordPress with Capistrano](<a href="http://theme.fm/2011/08/tutorial-deploying-wordpress-with-capistrano-2082/">http://theme.fm/2011/08/tutorial-deploying-wordpress-with-capistrano-2082/</a>)</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WordPress deployment using Capistrano]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/03/02/wordpress-deployment-using-capistrano/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-02T11:45:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/03/02/wordpress-deployment-using-capistrano</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Acquinity Interactive hired me</h1>

<p>I was recently hired by a marketing company to help them rebrand their digital presence. While this word is loaded with meaning, they wanted me to help them make a new website. The process is allowing me to start a development process from the complete beginning. Most interestingly, Im able to do things the right way.</p>

<h2>Why WordPress?</h2>

<p>I decided to use WordPress as the framework for their website. As a company of more than 250 employees, they need something that can be easily managed by otherwise untrained individuals. A straightforward CMS like WordPress is perfect for this job.  For me, I prototype the website using Foundation from Zurb, then with the creative director, I find the right &ldquo;style&rdquo; of the website. Once we get past deciding the technical details, I can just go into WordPress and make page templates that fit out prototyped site. By using WordPress, I know that once I get past the html/css prototypes, I can translate the pages into php template files that will be populated from the administrative panel.</p>

<h2>Why Capistrano?</h2>

<p>This is a good question. People who think of WordPress either think of the SaaS version (wordpress.com) or blogs. Most people don&rsquo;t consider it requiring a development process or a deployment strategy. Personally, I hate wasting time on things that don&rsquo;t need to have time wasted on. I love to learn something new, but if I can find out how to automate a process, I&rsquo;m going to take the initial time to set it up. By automating the deployment process, I know I can have consistent development environments.</p>

<p>Capistrano is a Ruby based package that runs SSH commands. Its largely used with Rails applications to manage various development environments (local/staging/production). Its great because at a touch of <code>cap deploy</code> you have your website up and running. Better yet, if you find out something broke, you just just <code>cap deploy:rollback</code>. In short, it&rsquo;s pretty amazing because no longer do you need a designated &ldquo;deployment&rdquo; person. Instead, you can take time before your project begins to have the deployment strategy set up.</p>

<h2>Why do you need development environments?</h2>

<p>I won&rsquo;t go to much into this because it&rsquo;s one of the basic tenants of web development. Have a place where you develop (local), have a test environment where the site is as close to live without being live (testing), and have a separate place to have a autonomous production environment which will not be disrupted. One of the issues with these environments is that you have different files that you may be changing, but are not consistently updated.</p>

<p>You don&rsquo;t want to screw up a site when other people may be using it. In the worst case scenario, you have files that you are working on a live site. Maybe you use the WordPress code editor, or maybe your using an FTP program to just edit the files directly on the server. In this situation, if you have a boo-boo, but don&rsquo;t know whats wrong, you could lose traffic and confuse users.</p>

<p>In a slightly better situation, you have a local development environment and a production server. This is pretty normal. You might make your changes to your WordPress theme via a local server. You make sure the files are working and the visuals render properly. Once you like the final product, you will push the updated files through FTP. If you are really good, you will update the files via SSH.</p>

<p>The first example (aka cowboy coding) is all bad. The second example is not so obvious for some people. To explain most basically, FTP is very slow and error prone. Its not impossible to use FTP for site management, but its very likely that batch uploads will result in significant failed files. Yes, you can always make sure the files work by looking through your log. The point is you want to find a solution that doesn&rsquo;t have any problems.</p>

<h2>Enter Capistrano</h2>

<p>Capistrano lets you have your local environment mirrored in other places. You can set certain folders that are not mirrored (i.e. file uploads, config files, etc), so that your updates to the site are fast and targeted. Capistrano uses SSH and Git to create your extended servers. By setting up Capistrano, you just need to develop using basic version control methods. If you already use Git normally, Capistrano is perfect for you.</p>

<p>Setting up Capistrano is a bit difficult for non-Ruby developers (aka me). There is some syntax that takes getting used to, but once you figure out the gist, its a walk in the park. Theres nothing more fulfilling than working at something that seems so foreign and finally seeing it work.</p>

<p>The tutorial I used to setup my server were by <a href="http://theme.fm/">Konstantin Kovshenin</a> from Automattic. The lists that I found most useful are below.</p>

<p><a href="http://theme.fm/2011/08/tutorial-deploying-wordpress-with-capistrano-2082/">Deploying WordPress with Capistrano</a></p>

<p><a href="http://theme.fm/2011/09/deploying-wordpress-with-capistrano-part-2-staging-servers-tagging-database-security-2213/">Deploying wordPress with Capistrano Part 2: Staging Servers, Tagging &amp; Database Security</a></p>

<p><a href="http://theme.fm/2011/11/deploying-wordpress-with-capistrano-part-3-backing-up-and-restoring-mysql-2922/">Deploying WordPress with Capistrano Part 3: Backing Up and Restoring MySQL</a></p>

<p>Additionally, the Capistrano website has a series of links for using Capistrano on WordPress services.</p>

<p><a href="http://capistranorb.com/">http://capistranorb.com/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yeoman EADDRINUSE error fix]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/03/01/yeoman-eaddrinuse-error-fix/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-01T11:59:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/03/01/yeoman-eaddrinuse-error-fix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Yeoman</h1>

<p>I recently fell into the bandwagon of Yeoman. After spending time with Peepcode screencasts to deepen my understanding of jQuery, javascript and MVC frameworks, I decided TDD and Grunt were crucial to m y development process. Having people like Chris Coyer and Paul Irish on my radar made me finally fess up and get Yeoman running locally.</p>

<h2>Getting Running</h2>

<p>Issue with running Yeoman is initially my allergic reaction to automated terminal commands. I am not always fond of seeing foreign words run by my command line, but I try my best to understand what they are doing.</p>

<p>Grunt installs itself when you run <code>Yo Webapp</code>. Theres little you need to do to have working scaffolded application with TDD &lsquo;infrastructure&rsquo; in place (aka Mocha, Grunt, JSLint, etc). When you follow the directions from Yeoman.io, its easy to get the web app running</p>

<h2>Problems</h2>

<p>I started having problems when I wanted to run <code>Grunt server</code>. When I ran <code>Grunt</code> alone, the process ran without any problems. For some reason, when I tried to test the server, Grunt would hang up on LiveReload. Specifically, I got this message:</p>

<pre><code>Running "server" task

Running "clean:server" (clean) task

Running "coffee:dist" (coffee) task
&gt;&gt; Destination not written because compiled files were empty.

Running "compass:server" (compass) task
Nothing to compile. If you're trying to start a new project, you have left off the directory argument.
Run "compass -h" to get help.

Running "livereload-start" task
... Starting Livereload server on 35729 ...

... Uhoh. Got error listen EADDRINUSE ...
Error: listen EADDRINUSE
    at errnoException (net.js:769:11)
    at Server._listen2 (net.js:909:14)
    at listen (net.js:936:10)
    at Server.listen (net.js:985:5)
    at Server.listen (/Users/lkbogdonoff/sites/portfolio/node_modules/grunt-contrib-livereload/node_modules/tiny-lr/lib/server.js:133:15)
    at Object.startLRServer (/Users/lkbogdonoff/sites/portfolio/node_modules/grunt-contrib-livereload/lib/utils.js:21:11)
    at Object.module.exports (/Users/lkbogdonoff/sites/portfolio/node_modules/grunt-contrib-livereload/tasks/livereload.js:44:20)
    at Object.task.registerTask.thisTask.fn (/Users/lkbogdonoff/sites/portfolio/node_modules/grunt/lib/grunt/task.js:78:16)
    at Object.Task.start._running (/Users/lkbogdonoff/sites/portfolio/node_modules/grunt/lib/util/task.js:282:30)
    at Task.runTaskFn (/Users/lkbogdonoff/sites/portfolio/node_modules/grunt/lib/util/task.js:235:24)
</code></pre>

<p>I posted a bug report to the Yeoman Github repository <a href="https://github.com/yeoman/yeoman/issues/938">here</a> and pinged <a href="https://github.com/sindresorhus">sindresorhus</a>. Within a day, another user replied on the Github issue thread explaining he had the same issue. Similarly, Sindre Sorhus also pitched in to help.</p>

<h2>Solution</h2>

<p>Eventually, I didn&rsquo;t figure out what would solve the problem. I found a stop-gap measure which lets me continue running <code>grunt server</code> and have a local copy run without issues.</p>

<p>In Grunt.js, I needed to remove the line calling <code>livereload-start</code>. I did this by changing the grunt.task.run like this:</p>

<pre><code>grunt.registerTask('server', function (target) {
    if (target === 'dist') {
        return grunt.task.run(['build', 'open', 'connect:dist:keepalive']);
    }

    grunt.task.run([
        'clean:server',
        'coffee:dist',
        'compass:server',
      //'livereload-start',
        'connect:livereload',
        'open',
        'watch'
    ]);
});
</code></pre>

<h2>Reflection</h2>

<p>Even through I had googled portions of the error code in hopes of finding someone with a similar situation, there were no people with my exact situation. As a result, I thought about updating my Gems, Command-Line Tools and various brew packages. The Github issues response time was great. I&rsquo;ll keep trying to get a better understanding of how to use Yeoman. For the time being it works!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Soka Education Conference 2013: Day 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/02/16/soka-education-conference-2013-day-1/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-16T20:50:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/02/16/soka-education-conference-2013-day-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>  &ldquo;I feel like we are dueling with lightsabers&rdquo; -Spady</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conclusion from the Soka Education Conference Paper]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/02/11/conclusion-from-the-soka-education-conference-paper/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-11T01:02:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/02/11/conclusion-from-the-soka-education-conference-paper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>I wrote a paper titled &ldquo;Soka Education and Digital Education Technologies: Massively Open Online Courses,&rdquo; for the 2013 Soka Education Student Research Project conference. The following section is the conclusion.</em></p>

<h1>Conclusion</h1>

<p>Soka educationâ€™s philosophical framework for teaching and learning is appropriate for the emerging to the newly emerging educational technology field. This papers goal was to help draw attention to a field that is quickly emerging with good intentions. The growth and social cause makes it attractive to both educators, entrepreneurs, and investors. Having such a great impact on the students, it must be carefully traversed. In references to evidence oriented progress, Makiguchi states:</p>

<blockquote><p>â€œWe must strictly avoid following ideologies of uncertain origin that cannot be substantiated by actual proof-even if they may be the most time-honored tradition-and thereby sacrificing the precious lives of others and ourselves.â€</p></blockquote>

<p>The education technologies too must be scrutinized to insure they are being implemented for the correct reasons. While MOOCs and other tools may benefit schools in reducing costs and increasing profits, the fundamental question should revolve around how they improve a students learning opportunity.</p>

<p>The digital technologies emerging in the education space are seeking to improve student-centered learning opportunities, but the educational technology space is not new. In the past five years, investors funding emerging private educational technology enterprises has quadrupled. These investments are spurring ventures such as MOOCs, but are still building profit-seeking entities. As a result, the driving forces behind Soka education are invaluable for reflecting on the purpose of education technology companies. Traditionally disruptive technology companies must be extremely careful in their disruption of existing educational markets. While emerging digital technologies can undoubtedly offer value to improving student experiences, many systems are already healthy.</p>

<p>The MOOC field is targeted at student-centeredness in a way that is inline with Soka Education. Just as the MOOCs themselves are not innately good or bad, their application must be continually considered. Companies like Udacity and Coursera are already holding classes that are eligible for actual college credit in American universities. The MOOCs are will help colleges reduce the cost of classes, expand course selection for students, and continue growing the discussion on the application of digital technology to education. The digital tools redefine â€œstudent-centerednessâ€ by allow students to personalize their learning experiences in ways less prone to budget and institutional capacity.</p>

<h2>Future Research</h2>

<p>Future research should further analyze the following points from the perspective of Soka education: MOOC course rights, digital resource copyright clearance, hybrid teaching pedagogies, the usage of other multimedia tools for student learning, and the efficacy of video based learning materials. These topics could each be the basis for extensive research to further the field of student-centered education using digital technologies.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digesting Reads | The Trial]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/02/07/digesting-reads-%7C-the-trial/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-07T11:42:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/02/07/digesting-reads-|-the-trial</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>&ldquo;The Trial&rdquo; Kafka</h1>

<p><em>Starting off with the face that I needed some New York in my life. Digging the people, the architecture, the little coffee shops and busy subways.</em></p>

<h2>First two chapters.</h2>

<p>Kafka writes <strong>The Trial</strong> in a slight mysterious plot line that Im not used to reading. Reading the news and twitter streams has made me expect the core of the manner in a short burst. <strong>The Trial</strong> lays out a plot line by painting a clear picture and scene. The scene is filled with distinct emotional expression and tension, but there are no defined characters or causes. In a buddhist explanation, <strong>The Trial</strong> describes the world through effects, rather than causes.</p>

<h2>Home invasion</h2>

<p>The book begins with an abrupt awakening of the main character. Two men disrupt K. from his morning regime of breakfast and preparing for work. Instead, he is observed and kept from leaving his room. He is arrested.</p>

<p>The arrest is not explained to the reader or the main character and unfolds into the dangers of a hierarchical authority system. The figures arresting K. do not know why he is being arrested, but feel quite justified in their restriction of K.&rsquo;s freedom. The invasion of privacy, disruption of personal space, and disregard for another&rsquo;s humanity is seen in so many facets of society. The authority figures are not alone in their expression.</p>

<p>K., who hopes to reclaim his dignity, seeks answers. After being detained in his own home, he encounters the figure of higher command who personally interview the detainee. K., who continues seeking the cause for the injustices of the morning, encounters yet another response absent of reason. The invading figures freely roam K.&rsquo;s home and declare their departure.</p>

<h2>Court appearance</h2>

<p>Forced to face his day without comprehending the complete background of the morning&rsquo;s events, K. braves the rest of his day at work. Left only with a notion that he is expected to appear in court, he is forced to make assumptions as to his appearance date. Again, lacking all information to help understand the situation, K. decides to make his way to the courts on the first potential day court gathers.</p>

<p>Finding his way to the courthouse is no simple task. K. wanders the neighborhood and buildings near the courthouse, hoping to glimpse upon the place of his belonging. K. discovers the courthouse only too late and is forced to stand trial the moment of his arrival. Again, no explanation, he is placed in front of, what seems to be a divided courthouse.</p>

<p>Giving his all, K. argues for the injustices he is forced to undergo. Again, little understanding behind the disruption&rsquo;s cause makes the argument one of unwarranted personal invasion.</p>

<h2>Realm of foreign rules</h2>

<p>Throughout K.&rsquo;s series of events, the reader is left to wonder how easily the same events could happen to themselves. K. is a everyday well respected citizen. There is little that he did to provoke these events. More so, he seems to do everything in proper order to understand the dilemma, but is given no regard.</p>

<p>Replace K.&rsquo;s story with any individual, young or old, and <strong>The Trial</strong> reflects their own experience in a judicial system. When expected to defend oneself in a realm of foreign rules, it matters little that there is any reason at all. The senselessness of the book&rsquo;s plot captures closely the &ldquo;in the moment&rdquo; activity one is forced to experience in any mode of heavy jurisdiction.</p>

<p>The digestion of events is difficult in foreign systems of operation. More so, in moments of extreme consequence, the notion of clear reflection is nearly impossible.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
