<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Leonard Kiyoshi Bogdonoff]]></title>
  <link href="http://lkbgift.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lkbgift.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-07T20:17:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://lkbgift.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Leonard Kiyoshi Bogdonoff]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[lkbgift@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Traveling to meet and learn]]></title>
    <link href="http://lkbgift.github.com/blog/2013/01/07/traveling-to-meet-and-learn/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-07T10:56:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lkbgift.github.com/blog/2013/01/07/traveling-to-meet-and-learn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/FpETP.png" title="New Mexico, Texas, the Bay Area, Detroit, New York, Boston, and Washington DC" alt="My trip" /></p>

<h1>Enter US</h1>

<p>I returned back to the US on December 24th (approximately two weeks ago). I overcame a week of jetlag, where I was waking up at 4 AM every morning and going to bed by 8pm. Not such a bad habit if you ask me. Before returning, I decided I was going to do a bit of traveling in the US, knowing that I was going to bunkerdown in Orange County, while finishing up some remaining school tasks. I planned a trip to <a href="http://i.imgur.com/FpETP.png">New Mexico, Texas, the Bay Area, Detroit, New York, Boston, and Washington DC</a>.</p>

<p>Honestly, I have no idea why I planned the trip. I had some places that I knew I wanted to visit (Im looking at you Detroit), but no concrete reasons or goals. I sort of decided that I needed to look at jobs, I needed to reintroduce myself to cities in the US after being China for a year, and finally I needed to see friends.</p>

<p>Immediately after getting into Aliso Viejo, I thought I had caught a cold. The opposite timezones threw off my internal clock. I decided I needed to get a jumpstart on aclimating to US life and started a process of reaching out to old clients and meeting new web developers.</p>

<p>My first step started in China. I used Reddit&#8217;s /r/webdev community to start asking people if they were interested in partnering to work together on projects. I was up at 3am trying to finalize some client work when I decided it would be a good idea to look for co-workers. The <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/Wordpress/comments/14ztvk/anyone_interested_in_working_together/">result</a> was suprising. I had respondents from Japan, Ireland, and Los Angeles.</p>

<p>Being the internet, I did my best to create a concrete bond beyond a Reddit comment. I got skype/email contact information and started coordinating some direct contact. The Japan and Ireland connections were both quite experienced web developers in their field. On was a designer (Ireland) and the other a security expert (Japan).</p>

<p>The user from Los Angeles was most interesting, because he was the one I was most likely to meet. Los Angeles connection was a PHP developer and offered to meet when I arrived back in the US.</p>

<p><img src="http://new.tinygrab.com/c00843a9616ff8c5ede1b40f097fb25b2a7699985a.png" title="Wordpress developers?" alt="Reddit post /r/webdev" /></p>

<h1>Networking through Reddit</h1>

<p>I met Dan Morgan the third day I returned from China. Not being able to drive, my father graciously took time to drive me up to LA. I met with Dan over dinner, where I promised to cover the tab in exchange for his time.</p>

<p>My goal was to get as much exposure to the developer community in Los Angeles. I was looking to justify my interest in being a frontend developer in Los Angeles, as well as look for some validation in my experience in China. Having been out of the country and never apart of the professional web development community in California (or the US), I felt meeting people already in the field was the best step.</p>

<p>My conversation with Dan started out with him trying to guide me in the right direction. I was looking for what organizations I should watch out for, what meet ups I should be looking to join, and where I would be most efficient at meeting people who valued the work I had to offer. Dan answered my questions by guiding me to looking into the design firm Huge. He also alluded to the fact that there was a inflated value toward UX designers in Los Angeles.</p>

<p>Our conversation quickly shifted to how we could be mutually useful to one another. First I understood that he had personal projects of his own (as most developers should/do). I also was able to validate my own experience in China by realizing that not all people had experience with the LEAN startup methodology. More so, I realized that my experience organizing tech meetups and events was a valuable experience that would be useful in the context of networking.</p>

<p>Overall Dan was very enlightening. He made me realize there are different kinds of developers. To be blunt, people like Dan are very talented but not aware of the many opportunities around. Dan is the type of person would look for an easy solution available to making money. He was not interested in working hard for someone elses idea.</p>

<p>This attitiude was not because Dan was lazy, but because he was tired of developing other people&#8217;s ideas without being properlly rewarded. I saw this in some sense a result of being jaded by the community. This showed me that if I continue to do work for others, I need to enter contracts/relationships with the understanding that I need to cover my bases from the beginning. Rather than expecting to be rewarded in the future for work in the past, I need to make sure I am rewarded in the present.</p>

<p><img src="http://new.tinygrab.com/c00843a961ee8fcc05cfbfc0a80a5ece6ef38842c6.png" title="Reddit post in /r/Arizona" alt="Reddit to the rescue" /></p>

<h2>Reddit to the rescue (again)</h2>

<p>Next step, I drove to New Mexico with Ryan. We decided to go the scenic route through the native American reservations in Arizona. Our route took us through parts of Arizona where we didnt know anybody. We needed a place to sleep, but  were also keeping to a restricted budget.</p>

<p>Our trip began on New Years day and we were going to need to find ap l ace to stay on that evening. We expected to be in Flagstaff or Sedona Arizona (approximately 400 miles from our final destination). Also, little did we know that the nightly temperature was below 0 degrees fahrenheit. This meant no sleeping in the car.</p>

<p>On December 31st, I <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/arizona/comments/15qsmr/can_anyone_in_flagstaff_host_my_friend_and_i_for/">posted</a> on the /r/Arizona sub-reddit that we were looking for a place to stay on the night of the first. To my pleasant suprise, a redditor took up the  call to host myself and my friend. Mind you, complete strangers.</p>

<p>Zach, in all his willingness, was okay with us coming to his house at 11pm (our expected arrival time). He gave us his room (where he had a couch and bed) and told us to make outselves at home. We met for no more than 5 minutes, because he had to be up for work the next morning at 5am. He even left before we woke up in the morning, so by the time we left, we never even got to say bye.</p>

<p>I am extremely grateful for his willingness to host us. Ryan and I left a small gift (a book, photos, and chocolates) to say thanks. Apart from some text message exchanges, we didnt otherwise communicate. Before leaving, Ryan and I cleaned up the room. We tried to leave the place cleaner than when we arrived.</p>

<p>Overall, loving the network opportunities coming from Reddit. Highly recommend it to others looking to connect with new job markets or looking for places to live!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Waterfall (web) development sucks]]></title>
    <link href="http://lkbgift.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/waterfall-development-sucks/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T09:25:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lkbgift.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/waterfall-development-sucks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is for the people who need to hire developers, but don&#8217;t understand how to make a website. This is for the person who doesn&#8217;t know where to start, but knows what they don&#8217;t want. In fact, this is perfect for the person who knows what they don&#8217;t want and also has an idea of what they would like.</p>

<p>As a developer, being able to build what the clients needs (and not just what they want) is the sign of success. Sure, I could build a site with the newest technology to impress my friends and fatten my portfolio, but this ignores what I&#8217;m being paid to do. Im being paid to insure the client&#8217;s company is successful and effective in establishing a digital facing extension.</p>

<p>Designing and programming is not so hard, but knowing what to build can  make or break of a project. Your developer should do everything to lead you to success. A failed project is the consequence of a failed developer. A good foundation will result in a successful website.</p>

<p>When it comes to making websites, you can bill by the hour or by the project. You can pay X00$/hr to a well skilled developer. You can also pay a X,000,000 - X00,000 figure to develop a full scale website for your company. In either case, your focus is to get the most bang for your buck. You are looking to pay someone to lead you to success.</p>

<p>Your developers goal should not be justifying how much they are being paid. Your developers responsibility is making sure your digital presence successfully and effectively solves your problem. A web developer is a creator of solutions</p>

<p>Regardless of how you decide to pay, you need to understand there are different ways of developing. The traditional methods from the past decade is based on the &#8220;waterfall&#8221; method. The &#8220;waterfall&#8221; method depends on designing a website specification, signing a bloated contract, then pushing the contract through its individual &#8220;steps&#8221;.</p>

<p>Traditionally, your web developer will &#8220;design&#8221; the mockups of the website in an image editor like Photoshop. They will provide you a few examples of what individual pages may look like, and be sure to charge you for each mockup. Next, they will &#8220;code&#8221; the mockup into their preferred web framework (hopefully they are at least using a CMS) and then present you with what was intended to be <em>the design</em>.</p>

<p>100% of the time (yes, 100%), at least one side is surprised by the outcomes. The coded version of the site resembles the original design, but reveals the many points where discussion was lacking and incomplete. Additionally, when the coded mockup is viewed across devices and browsers, it completely loses it&#8217;s structure and fails.</p>

<p>Wait, theres more! Your &#8220;waterfall&#8221; developer recommends this methods because they believe it will expidite the website development process. They also make it known that you are limited in the number of changes you are allowed to make. Or they make sure you know the cost of making changes.</p>

<p>So wait, your wondering if theres an alternative. You believe, &#8220;this is how developing websites works. Its painful, costly, and both side leave having to make sacrifices&#8221;. In fact, that sounds more like poor congressional politics than web development.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s not the only way. (To be continued)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Foundation from Zurb]]></title>
    <link href="http://lkbgift.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/zurb-foundation/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-16T11:59:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lkbgift.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/zurb-foundation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>TLDR: The SASS Zurb Foundation install makes it easy to make a fully customized responsive website.</strong></p>

<p>Making a new website can be extremely easy or very time consuming. Tools available through Opensource projects, Creative Commons, and GNU licenses make it easy to layout a prototype in no time.</p>

<p>Some of the obvious ones are <a href="http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap/">Twitter Bootstrap</a> (+20,000 stars on Github) and <a href="http://html5boilerplate.com/">HTML5 Boilerplate</a>. My personal recent favorite is <a href="http://foundation.zurb.com/">Foundation</a> from <a href="http://zurb.com/">Zurb</a>. I took a liking to Foundation because it gave me an edge at mocking up marketing pages without having to go through an extensive design and copywriting process.</p>

<p>Zurb&#8217;s Foundation uses <a href="http://compass-style.org/">Compass</a> and <a href="http://sass-lang.com/">SASS</a> to make getting started and customizing very easy. You don&#8217;t have to track down CSS elements or worse, overwrite existing declarations. Foundation provides clear documentation regarding what is provided and how it can be used.</p>

<p>When paired with Compass, Foundation compiles a series of &#8220;Foundational&#8221; SASS stylesheets into a clearly documented CSS file. The SASS files make use of the <a href="http://thecodingdesigner.com/tutorials/variables-css-sass">variable notation</a>, allowing new users to change the existing styles, rather than overwriting. This can be particularly useful when you are trying to keep your CSS clean and well documented.</p>

<p>To make changes, Foundation provides a file called <a href="http://foundation.zurb.com/docs/sass.php">_settings.sass</a>. This file has all of the variables available for customization. All variables are presented commented out, so to make changes, just uncomment and change. Rather than overwriting the existing selectors, this keeps the CSS selectors light and easy to manage (<a href="http://smacss.com/">Snooks</a> would approve).</p>

<p>Foundation makes a webpage look really great from the beginning (like Twitter Bootstrap). Some of us don&#8217;t like the default Helvetica Neue and recognizable colors.  Differentiating your installation of Foundation is easy. The <a href="http://zurb.com/">problem</a> with Twitter Bootstrap is that most websites using it don&#8217;t do enough altercations to make it look different.</p>

<p>The two major changes that make your website look different are changing the default colors and the fonts. Again, using the SASS <a href="http://foundation.zurb.com/docs/sass.php">_settings</a> file, you only make changes to the $mainColor, $bodyFontFamily, and $headerFontFamily. Once these changes are made, you have a extremely unique, responsive, well functioning website.</p>

<p>One letdown of Foundation is the dependence on <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/CSS2/box.html">box-model</a>. (Let it be know, I <a href="http://paulirish.com/2012/box-sizing-border-box-ftw/">love box-model</a> too. Still, it doesn&#8217;t work with old browsers.) Box-model as a CSS property which calculates the padding inside the width. This simplifies calculating percentages for fluid layouts, but sadly this property is not available in IE6.</p>

<p>Fortunately the dependance on box-model can be circumvented with <a href="https://github.com/h5bp/mobile-boilerplate/wiki/Media-Queries-Polyfill">polyfills</a> and <a href="https://github.com/zurb/foundation/issues/684">explicitly defined layouts</a>. Still, Foundation&#8217;s development without consideration for older browsers makes it difficult to use for my current demographic.</p>

<p>Overall, Foundation makes it easy to build websites. Paired with <a href="http://incident57.com/codekit/">Codekit</a> (which deserves a post of its own) or <a href="http://compass-style.org/">Compass</a>, starting and managing new sites enjoyable!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple's Magic Mouse Disconnect Problem]]></title>
    <link href="http://lkbgift.github.com/blog/2012/12/12/apples-magic-mouse-disconnect-problem/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-12T10:24:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lkbgift.github.com/blog/2012/12/12/apples-magic-mouse-disconnect-problem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>TLDR: Stick some aluminum wads between the mouse and the battery&#8217;s (+) connector.</strong></p>

<p>Apple&#8217;s Magic Mouse is a great tool for Mac owners. The engineering behind the <a href="http://www.patentlyapple.com/patently-apple/2009/11/new-magic-mouse-secrets-revealed-in-apple-patent.html">multitouch technology</a> is undeniably advanced. Its responsive, sleak, and easy to carry around. The multitouch functionality allows you to flip through pages on your OSX screen and access your dashboard with ease. The touch scrolling technology creates a whole new way to browse webpages.</p>

<p>Recently, my Magic Mouse has been disconnecting frequently. I was unsure of the problem source and assumed it was related to frequently carrying the mouse in my bag. Although there was no visible damage to the mouse itself, the frequent disconnection made it nearly impossible to use.</p>

<p>Google search for &#8220;Magic Mouse Disconnect&#8221; and you find similar grievances on <a href="https://discussions.apple.com/thread/2217770?start=90&amp;tstart=0" title="Apple's Discussion Board">Apple&#8217;s own forums</a>. One product owner went as far as replacing a fleet of Magic Mouses for his iMacs. A seemingly costly investment. Others reverted from the wireless conveneince to the alternate wired mice.</p>

<p>Sadly, the extensive replacements were done in vain. The source of the problem is not damage related, but rather a poor design on Apples part. The Magic Mouse&#8217;s battery compartment expends the (+) end of batteries to stick out a lot. This is a problem when you are using poorly made discount batteries.</p>

<p>The solution is to stuff a wad of aluminum foil between the batteries and the mouse&#8217;s (+) connectors. This seems like a solution that could have been easily solved with better engineering. I just feel bad for the guy who disposed of all the perfectly functional Magic Mice.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
