<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: website, | Leonard Kiyoshi Bogdonoff]]></title>
  <link href="http://lkbgift.github.com/blog/categories/website-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lkbgift.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-06T17:46:19-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://lkbgift.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Leonard Kiyoshi Bogdonoff]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[lkbgift@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Waterfall (web) development sucks]]></title>
    <link href="http://lkbgift.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/waterfall-development-sucks/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T09:25:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://lkbgift.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/waterfall-development-sucks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is for the people who need to hire developers, but don't understand how to make a website. This is for the person who doesn't know where to start, but knows what they don't want. In fact, this is perfect for the person who knows what they don't want and also has an idea of what they would like.</p>

<p>As a developer, being able to build what the clients needs (and not just what they want) is the sign of success. Sure, I could build a site with the newest technology to impress my friends and fatten my portfolio, but this ignores what I'm being paid to do. Im being paid to insure the client's company is successful and effective in establishing a digital facing extension.</p>

<p>Designing and programming is not so hard, but knowing what to build can  make or break of a project. Your developer should do everything to lead you to success. A failed project is the consequence of a failed developer. A good foundation will result in a successful website.</p>

<p>When it comes to making websites, you can bill by the hour or by the project. You can pay X00$/hr to a well skilled developer. You can also pay a X,000,000 - X00,000 figure to develop a full scale website for your company. In either case, your focus is to get the most bang for your buck. You are looking to pay someone to lead you to success.</p>

<p>Your developers goal should not be justifying how much they are being paid. Your developers responsibility is making sure your digital presence successfully and effectively solves your problem. A web developer is a creator of solutions</p>

<p>Regardless of how you decide to pay, you need to understand there are different ways of developing. The traditional methods from the past decade is based on the "waterfall" method. The "waterfall" method depends on designing a website specification, signing a bloated contract, then pushing the contract through its individual "steps".</p>

<p>Traditionally, your web developer will "design" the mockups of the website in an image editor like Photoshop. They will provide you a few examples of what individual pages may look like, and be sure to charge you for each mockup. Next, they will "code" the mockup into their preferred web framework (hopefully they are at least using a CMS) and then present you with what was intended to be <em>the design</em>.</p>

<p>100% of the time (yes, 100%), at least one side is surprised by the outcomes. The coded version of the site resembles the original design, but reveals the many points where discussion was lacking and incomplete. Additionally, when the coded mockup is viewed across devices and browsers, it completely loses it's structure and fails.</p>

<p>Wait, theres more! Your "waterfall" developer recommends this methods because they believe it will expedite the website development process. They also make it known that you are limited in the number of changes you are allowed to make. Or they make sure you know the cost of making changes.</p>

<p>So wait, your wondering if theres an alternative. You believe, "this is how developing websites works. Its painful, costly, and both side leave having to make sacrifices". In fact, that sounds more like poor congressional politics than web development.</p>

<p>It's not the only way. (To be continued)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
