<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: hardware, | Leonard Kiyoshi Bogdonoff]]></title>
  <link href="http://lkbgift.github.com/blog/categories/hardware-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lkbgift.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-07T20:17:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://lkbgift.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Leonard Kiyoshi Bogdonoff]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[lkbgift@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple's Magic Mouse Disconnect Problem]]></title>
    <link href="http://lkbgift.github.com/blog/2012/12/12/apples-magic-mouse-disconnect-problem/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-12T10:24:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://lkbgift.github.com/blog/2012/12/12/apples-magic-mouse-disconnect-problem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>TLDR: Stick some aluminum wads between the mouse and the battery's (+) connector.</strong></p>

<p>Apple's Magic Mouse is a great tool for Mac owners. The engineering behind the <a href="http://www.patentlyapple.com/patently-apple/2009/11/new-magic-mouse-secrets-revealed-in-apple-patent.html">multitouch technology</a> is undeniably advanced. Its responsive, sleak, and easy to carry around. The multitouch functionality allows you to flip through pages on your OSX screen and access your dashboard with ease. The touch scrolling technology creates a whole new way to browse webpages.</p>

<p>Recently, my Magic Mouse has been disconnecting frequently. I was unsure of the problem source and assumed it was related to frequently carrying the mouse in my bag. Although there was no visible damage to the mouse itself, the frequent disconnection made it nearly impossible to use.</p>

<p>Google search for "Magic Mouse Disconnect" and you find similar grievances on <a href="https://discussions.apple.com/thread/2217770?start=90&amp;tstart=0" title="Apple's Discussion Board">Apple's own forums</a>. One product owner went as far as replacing a fleet of Magic Mouses for his iMacs. A seemingly costly investment. Others reverted from the wireless conveneince to the alternate wired mice.</p>

<p>Sadly, the extensive replacements were done in vain. The source of the problem is not damage related, but rather a poor design on Apples part. The Magic Mouse's battery compartment expends the (+) end of batteries to stick out a lot. This is a problem when you are using poorly made discount batteries.</p>

<p>The solution is to stuff a wad of aluminum foil between the batteries and the mouse's (+) connectors. This seems like a solution that could have been easily solved with better engineering. I just feel bad for the guy who disposed of all the perfectly functional Magic Mice.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
