<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: self-teaching | Blog | RememberLenny]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/categories/self-teaching/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-04T16:02:05-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Leonard Kiyoshi Bogdonoff]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA["Failing into the pit of success"]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/06/01/failing-into-the-pit-of-success/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-01T09:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2013/06/01/failing-into-the-pit-of-success</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Why learn?</h1>

<p>I have spent the past three years developing websites. I have been hired by clients ranging from startups to fortune 500 corporations. Yet, I don&rsquo;t have any formal training as a computer scientist or digital designer. I went to school to study in a Liberal Arts program in the humanities. I read books on cultural theory, history, and adopted an obscure love for classical literature (Goethe I&rsquo;m looking at you).</p>

<p>So why does this all matter? Well, like most people, I wanted to get on the band wagon of utilizing the immense power available today in the form of technology. I saw computers as the beginning, but instantly knew before smart phones that mobile technologies were offering amazing opportunities through widely distributed data networks. I wanted to use this, but I didn&rsquo;t have any training. I think a lot of people around my age (and those who are not) have this feeling.</p>

<p>I started learning web development, and more recently Javascript. Javascript was my &ldquo;in&rdquo; to the growing digital frontier. Making a website was foreign to me, but I found people would pay me to do it, so I invested my time to get good at it. I identified the front-end (User Experience, User facing elements, Design) web development as most interesting to me.</p>

<h1>Deciding the front-end</h1>

<p>Deciding I would become prolific at front-end technologies (HTML/CSS/Javascript), I found myself struggling with the abstract concepts of Javascript. I also noticed that Javascript could potentially offer the most learning value. As the founder of Javascript says, &ldquo;Always bet on Javascript&rdquo;.</p>

<p>I traverse the infinitum of blog posts being written on software engineering to find the rare nuggets of informative learning resources. I find myself attracted by titles to blog posts, but unable to comprehend the complex code blocks. Instead, I browse the (often Jekyll or Octopress) blog posts, only to read the commentary and skip of the code segments.</p>

<p>My greatest obstacle when reading code is that I&rsquo;m feeling like I understand the code, but fail to absorb the lessons. Overcoming the mammoth that is learning to code by adopting good practices has significantly helped. I can confidently say, I am not good at learning over the internet or even teaching myself how to do &ldquo;stuff&rdquo;. Instead, I am good at identifying my faults in remembering and make up for it by creating processes that make me &ldquo;fail forward&rdquo;.</p>

<p>I know that I fail at absorbing coding concepts. I also know that I am good at learning from mistakes. I combine the two understandings about myself by forming a practice to force myself to fail at absorbing coding concepts by making guided mistakes. I do this without another teacher guiding me or a tutor.</p>

<p>Note: The term &ldquo;Failing into the pit of success&rdquo; was a term developed by a software developer at Microsoft.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
